'(PHONE RINGING)'>
"(MAN) Here's what's going to happen.">
"I'm gonna read this,\
and you're gonna listen,">
"and you're gonna stay on the line,\
and you're not gonna interrupt.">
"You're not gonna speak for any reason.">
'Some of this you know.'>
"I'm gonna start\
at the top of the page.">
'Meticulous, yes.'>
'Methodical. Educated.\
They were these things.'>
'Nothing extreme.\
Like anyone, they varied.'>
'There were days of mistakes\
and laziness and infighting.'>
"And there were days, good days,\
when by anyone's judgement">
'they would have to be considered clever.'>
'No one would say\
that what they were doing was complicated.'>
"It wouldn't even be considered new,\
except for maybe in the geological sense.">
'They took from their surroundings\
what was needed,'>
'and made of it something more.'>
'- I extended that.\
- Wait, what order date you put on this?'>
"- (PHILLIP) The 28th. Why? What do you care?\
- (ROBERT) I don't know...">
"- Yeah, I'm putting the 28th.\
- Have you...">
'Have you thought any more\
about what you want to put forward?'>
'- Uh, not really.\
- Because I was...'>
"I mean, I haven't changed my mind\
or anything.">
"Phillip and I were talking.\
We think it'd be good. It'd be fun.">
"Look, nobody's saying it wouldn't be fun.">
"It's just, the time for jacking around\
with Tesla coils">
'and ball lightning in the garage is over.'>
'Maybe this is something you should try\
on your own, in your free time, you know?'>
'My free time? Which free time?\
Free time after the 50 hours at work,'>
'after the 30 hours\
I already spend in that garage?'>
"- We're all working the same schedule.\
- (PHONE RINGING)">
"And it's not a Tesla coil.">
'I guess I could shave a couple of minutes\
off my day by eating on the toilet.'>
'Look, how many patents do we have?\
In the last 14 months?'>
'- Did you sign the agreement?\
- Nobody signed the agreement.'>
"It doesn't matter,\
we're sticking to the agreement.">
"(ABE) Name one other thing that's come\
out of that garage that's remotely profitable.">
"If you're talking about...">
"I don't see anybody quitting\
their jobs because of it.">
"I know I'm not. Are you?">
'(AARON) I think Abe just means\
that right now the JTAG cards are it.'>
'And when you look\
at the addresses on these things,'>
'we have a lot of apartments,\
a lot of residences.'>
'But these are not the bulk orders\
to OEMs or retail giants.'>
'- These are the quiet basement...\
- (ROBERT) Hackers.'>
"Yeah, hacker wannabes\
testing their dads' old motherboards.">
'And I know that a lot of that is my fault,\
admittedly, you know.'>
'With everything last year, and...\
the doubletalk we were getting from Platts'>
"and all the stuff\
we're not going to get into now...">
'(PHILLIP) Maybe we should get into it.'>
"I'm sorry. What?">
'(ROBERT) Go ahead. Tell him.'>
'Maybe we should get into it.\
I talked to my brother today.'>
'He knows of at least two other cases.'>
"We should at least let Platts know\
we're talking about it.">
'Forget Platts.'>
'This has got to start being about\
what has the best chance of going to market,'>
'and what is going to get us\
that VC attention.'>
'Look, I stuck by you guys\
when it was your turn,'>
"when I wasn't 100% sure\
of what we were doing,">
"or even if I didn't agree, maybe.">
'(WATER RUNNING)'>
"But if it's my turn,\
if we're still playing by the rules,">
'then this is what I want to try.'>
'(CROCKERY CLATTERING)'>
'- (KARA) Here, take it.\
- No, really.'>
"Oh, Robert, please.\
It's not going to hold.">
"- (ROBERT) It's going to go bad in my car.\
- It'll go bad here. OK, thanks.">
"- Good night, y'all.\
- See you.">
'We just got done\
giving this huge speech about this.'>
'- What, we gave a speech?\
- We just got done. It was five minutes ago.'>
"No, I gave a speech.\
I'm the one who forced the issue, remember?">
"And in fact, you know, they're onto us\
because I suck as a bad cop.">
"- I don't know about that.\
- You should do it. You could fake it better.">
"I don't know about that either.">
"Look, as long as we're going down this road\
where it's eighth-grade physics,">
'and happy fun time out in that garage,\
I think we could stand to try this.'>
"You know, Phillip and Robert\
are gung-ho on theirs, and that's fine.">
'But you know I have no interest in that.\
And I know you have no interest in that,'>
"besides the fact that Phillip and Robert\
don't even need us for what they want to do.">
'They just want to use the equipment.'>
"For what I want to do?\
We don't need them.">
"Not even Phillip,\
cos it doesn't need software.">
'- Is she asleep?\
- No, and she needs a bath.'>
"She's gonna wind up\
in the closet if I do it.">
"That's fine.">
"You know, even if Robert's OK with it,\
and he won't be,">
"I don't even think I understand\
what we're saying the thing's going to do.">
'I think we should let them go at it\
for the next two months.'>
'You know, they do theirs, we do ours.'>
"(KARA) They said it'd take 14 hours\
from the time we installed it.">
"Don't eat that.\
Don't eat that. Seriously, it's bad.">
'We have to throw the first\
couple of batches out. The filter.'>
'What about crushed?'>
'- (ROBERT) These guys are funded.\
- These guys are... What?'>
"- Liquid helium. These guys are funded.\
- No, that's what this is, OK?">
"That's the whole difference.\
That's what the box is.">
"This way we don't have to play\
the game where we're going back and forth">
'coming up with new and innovative ways\
to make the thing colder,'>
'- and generally unusable in the process.\
- (PHILLIP) Aaron, I need the hexagonal set.'>
'- And unmarketable.\
- Right, and unmarketable.'>
'By coming at it from the back end,'>
'see, rather than changing\
the surrounding temperature,'>
"we'll just change the level that it'll conduct,\
the transition temperature.">
'And, see, by bombarding these edges...'>
"What he's saying is, these guys,\
they're dropping the ceramic,">
'the temperature lower and lower.'>
'It makes the ceramic less resistant,\
knocks out the interior magnetic field.'>
"Exactly. What he's saying is...">
"What I'm saying is,\
we drop the box down on it.">
'OK? Focus our own magnetic field to negate,\
knock out with the inverse'>
"- what's going on inside the ceramic.\
- It's smart.">
'And that should change\
the transition temperature'>
'to something we can work with.'>
'- What are we saying that is?\
- Hopefully, near room temperature.'>
'What is that about\
the best mathematician is a lazy one?'>
'- What did you ask for?\
- (PHILLIP) I asked. I need the hexagonal set.'>
'- What did you call it?\
- (PHILLIP) Just come on.'>
'- Are these Type One?\
- The superconductors?'>
"- (BOTH) Yeah, they're Type One.\
- What? Is that going to be a problem?">
"There's plenty lying around at work,\
but they're all bar-coded, so...">
"- if I have to buy the kits, I'll buy the kits.\
- What are you doing about the source?">
'What?'>
'- I can get them.\
- You can... Are you sure?'>
"I thought you didn't like this idea anyways.">
"If you gotta buy 'em, you gotta buy 'em,\
but everything else we can take care of.">
'What are you doing about the source here?'>
'You know that story\
about how NASA spent millions of dollars'>
'developing this pen that writes in zero-G?'>
'- Did you ever read that?\
- Yeah.'>
'- And how Russia solved the problem?\
- Yeah, they used a pencil.'>
'Right, a normal wooden pencil.'>
'It just seems like Phillip takes\
the NASA route almost every time.'>
"- It's a palladium, right?\
- You got their diagram, what does it say?">
'They use a ratio of both,\
platinum and palladium.'>
"But I don't know if that's necessary.">
"I think they're just showing off.\
If you have it, you gotta use it, right?">
'I want to get a replacement router.'>
"- I'm putting down four ounces of palladium.\
- (AARON) Did Robert look at it?">
"- Yeah, I already got his eye.\
- (ROBERT) I can't fix it.">
"- OK. Where are you getting it?\
- Wal-Mart. It's like $50.">
'- OK. Can you get a receipt, please?\
- Yeah.'>
'Platinum or palladium is less resistant?'>
"- Abe.\
- Just, it's not a...">
"Yeah, I don't care.\
So resistance doesn't matter.">
'I need an aye or a yes.'>
'- Did you jiggle the...\
- Collet nut? Yeah.'>
'- Flip the...\
- Robert did it.'>
'Well, yes. Yeah, I guess. Aye.'>
'Well, then, which is cheaper?'>
"You're not going to buy it, are you?">
"Well, unless you've got\
a few grams of palladium lying around.">
'What?'>
"I'm just saying, why would they put it in there\
if you didn't need it?">
"One catalytic converter. It's fine.\
Just remember to put it back, OK?">
'Your emissions went up 300%.'>
'- Is there enough in here?\
- Yeah, should be.'>
"If not, we'll pull the one\
out of my truck.">
'OK, copper tubing.'>
'- This will be out of commission, right?\
- Without the tubing?'>
'- Yeah.\
- Yeah.'>
'We can use the Freon, too.'>
"No, I told you it's gonna be\
room temperature.">
'I know. Just in case.'>
"No, no, wait, wait. Aaron, stop, stop.\
I'll just buy the tubing.">
"This isn't saving us money.\
Wait. Did you cut anything?">
'- Hey, man. How are you?\
- Good, Jay.'>
'Should we be wearing goggles?'>
'- Should we be wearing goggles?\
- What?'>
'Goggles.\
Should we be wearing goggles?'>
"(AARON) Oh, wait, Phillip.\
You don't want to come out here.">
'(ABE) Phillip, grab a mask, OK?'>
"It is, though, right? It's not just me?">
"(AARON) No, it's definitely smaller, but...">
'I think it just seems that way.\
I mean, take what they have.'>
"OK, minus the coolant, OK?\
Which we don't need.">
'The rest of it is the mercury bath,'>
'which I mean,\
you would know better than I do,'>
"but they're probably just showing off.">
"I mean, if you have it,\
you've got to use it, right?">
"- (ABE) What? Does it hurt?\
- No, I didn't feel anything.">
'That sound is just weirding me out.'>
'Wow.'>
"- What does it feel like?\
- I don't know.">
"I don't know if I'm making it up.">
'Here.'>
"- Next part. Let's do the next part.\
- Yeah. Yeah.">
"Isn't there some sort of glass\
or transparent...">
"- I don't know.\
- Anything we can use as a window? Pyrex?">
"- Yeah, I'm in.\
- OK, drop it.">
"I don't know of anything\
that's not going to leave a gap in the field.">
"But we got to see what's going on in there.">
'- How much did that cost?\
- Yeah.'>
'- What?\
- You want to put my camcorder'>
"inside the box that's so dangerous\
we can't look into it.">
'(AARON) If something happens,\
would you pay me back?'>
'(ABE) So we have\
a slightly negative pressure in the box.'>
"So we're ready for the argon.">
"- Wait, which one is that?\
- It's the blue one.">
'- Blue one.\
- I weighed it at 77 grams.'>
'I set the scale to decagrams, though.'>
"I'm showing 7.7 decagrams.">
'Ready for...'>
'0.05 litres of argon.'>
'(HISSING)'>
'Ready?'>
"- Just the plate first, right?\
- Right, first just the plate, and then we'll...">
'(MACHINE HUMMING)'>
"OK, let's just give it a second.">
'- You want to do the box now?\
- Yeah.'>
"- OK, let's go through the checklist, then.\
- Aaron, hold on a second.">
"Let's make sure everything's set up right.\
Hold on, Aaron. Wait.">
'Just wait.'>
'OK.'>
'(MACHINE RUMBLING)'>
'Anything?'>
"- Is this normal?\
- I don't know...">
"- I'm turning it off.\
- Wait!">
"- No, it's frying my camera.\
- Not yet!">
'(MACHINE STOPS RUMBLING)'>
"OK, I didn't do that.">
'Did we blow something?'>
'Yeah, yeah, we did.'>
"That's destroyed.">
'- Here, you want to check your camera?\
- Yeah.'>
"Let's get this.">
'- You ready?\
- Yeah.'>
'One, two, three.'>
'(BUZZING)'>
'(PHONE BEEPING)'>
"- Hey.\
- (AARON) Hey, hey, tell me you're hungry.">
"Kara's at her mom's and I'm starving.">
"Uh... Yeah. Yeah, yeah,\
I'm hungry. What...">
"Abe, it's 7:00.">
"- 'Abe, it's 7:00 at night.\
- OK, yeah, I have food...">
'OK, OK. Wait, wait, wait.\
Are those kids there?'>
'Uh, just a sec.'>
"Yeah. Yeah, they're here.">
"OK, screw that, let's just go somewhere.\
I just pulled in, so come on down.">
'No, wait. Come up here first. I have\
some stuff I want to take back to the shop.'>
'All right, but meet me at the door.'>
'OK, all right.'>
"Seriously, meet me at the door.\
I'm coming up right now.">
"I'll do it. OK. All right.\
All right, see you.">
'(SIGNS) OK.'>
'(SIGHS) Hey, Brad.'>
'(CROWD CHEERING ON TV)'>
"What's up, Abe?">
'- Hey, Brad. How are you?\
- Good.'>
'(KNOCKING ON DOOR)'>
'How long did he say\
he was going to be there?'>
'Not long.'>
"I just think if he's got problems,\
he's got to fix them. You're not the guy's dad.">
'I know. I just thought it would be good\
to do something charitable.'>
'It definitely is charity.\
At least you admit that.'>
'Hey, you feel like a steak?'>
'To eat.'>
"No, I don't want a steak. Let's just grab\
some tacos on the way to the shop.">
'- I have some stuff I want to try out.\
- OK.'>
'Uh, we can get some tacos on the way,'>
'and I know where we can get\
a steak afterwards.'>
"What are you talking about?\
I'm not paying for a steak.">
"It's stable?">
"Aaron, it's stable?">
'- What did you do to this thing?\
- Huh? What?'>
'Looks like a dog digested it.'>
"OK, that's the plate.">
'I rigged this into the box\
so I could have some control over the feed.'>
"- I figured it's the easiest way...\
- This is controlling the box.">
'- Right, just the box.\
- The plate stays the same.'>
"Yeah, the plate's the same.\
What you do is you gradually feed it...">
'till...'>
'(MACHINE HUMMING)'>
"OK. You hear that? How it's, how it's...\
See, I'm not touching it anymore.">
"It's growing with its own momentum.">
"It's like a feedback loop,\
and it just regulates itself.">
'And what you do is,\
when it gets there...'>
'you bring it back,'>
'and there you go, it coasts.'>
"It's stable.\
It stays like that.">
'So, it works.'>
'- Yeah, it does.\
- What is that, like 10%?'>
'It knocks another couple of points off, too,\
by the time it reaches the peak.'>
'You may want to come over here\
and take a look at this.'>
'- OK, what am I looking at?\
- What are we pulling out of the batteries?'>
"I don't know, probably 24 volts.">
'- I mean, no more than that, right?\
- OK.'>
"So, your meter's jacked up.">
"That's what I figured. So, I tried three others.\
I got the exact same thing.">
'- I spent all last night...\
- What was it?'>
"I don't know. I spent all last night\
and a two-hour lunch break today">
'just double-checking everything.'>
"We're missing something.\
There's something wrong here.">
"We're not pulling out\
more than we're putting in.">
'- Slightly more.\
- Well, yeah, whatever.'>
"It's not like a volt and a half more\
than we're putting in.">
"I mean, it's probably the batteries.">
"They're cheap batteries, you know,\
probably not regulated right.">
'It is weird, though.'>
'You want to see something weirder?'>
"OK, let's go over this again.\
Two batteries, right? 24 volts?">
'What are we pulling out of this one?\
Just for fun.'>
'Twelve volts.'>
'- How about this one?\
- Should be 12 volts.'>
'So, what the hell is this thing?'>
"It doesn't stay like that.">
'No, I mean, it winds down in a few minutes,\
but what does that?'>
'(MACHINE HUM FADING)'>
"(AARON) I don't know.\
I'll tell them something.">
"I'll tell them we're spraying\
for bugs or something.">
'It should just be a day or two anyways.'>
"- Unless you want to bring them in.\
- No, no, it's just...">
'I mean, they have\
their work in there, too.'>
'You know, if Phillip finds out about that\
or even sees it,'>
"- he's going to have to take it apart.\
- I'm just putting a love tweak on it.">
"Yeah, I know. No, you're right.">
"Abe, it's my garage, OK?\
It's not like they're paying rent.">
'(MAN) There was value in the thing, clearly.\
That they were certain of.'>
'But what is the application?'>
'In a matter of hours, it was everything\
from mass transit to satellite launching.'>
'Imagining devices\
the size of jumbo jets.'>
'Everything would be cheaper.\
It was practical, and they knew it.'>
'But above all that,\
beyond the positives,'>
'they knew that the easiest way\
to be exploited'>
'is to sell something\
they did not yet understand.'>
'So they kept quiet.'>
'The parties would continue.\
Any birthday, anniversary, holiday,'>
"maybe some obscure project launch,\
it didn't matter. Any reason would do.">
'What was important is that Thomas Granger,\
their last, best hope of funding, show up.'>
"And if he left a little earlier\
than they would've liked,">
"well, he couldn't be blamed.">
'He was only there\
to please his daughter Rachel.'>
'And she was only there to please Abe.'>
'Hey, what did you say\
to Mr Granger earlier?'>
"- Did you flip my burger?\
- You can't call him Mr Granger.">
'You have to call him Thomas\
or something.'>
"- Go ahead, Robert. Flip it.\
- No, because he won't take you seriously.">
"- He's my dad's age.\
- But he thinks we're kids.">
"If you call him Mr Granger, he looks at you\
like you're a six-year-old kid.">
'He does it with me.'>
"- That's not going to work anymore.\
- Why do you have to be so...">
'(MAN) Abe had taken on the task\
of quantifying and explaining the device.'>
'But as weeks became months,\
their enthusiasm became a slow realisation'>
'that they were out of their depth.'>
"There he is.\
I've been calling you all morning.">
"- Where'd you call?\
- Your work and your cell.">
"I'm not there.">
'Really?'>
"- March madness?\
- It's Carolina and Michigan.">
"- Who's up?\
- I don't even know. What?">
'Do you have anything important\
at work today?'>
"I hope you're not implying\
that any day is unimportant at Cortex Semi.">
'No, no. Just... Look, I was going to come\
give you this big speech'>
"about how we've been friends for a long time\
and built up trust, and that whole big thing.">
'But how about this instead?'>
'If you ditch work this afternoon and promise\
to do the few small things that I ask you,'>
'I will in return show you\
the most important thing'>
'that any living organism\
has ever witnessed.'>
"- (AARON) Well, it looks like mustard to me.\
- (ABE) I know, but it's a film.">
"It's a protein secreted by a fungus\
called aspergillus ticor.">
'He told you that?'>
"No, he knew it was a protein,\
but he didn't know where it came from.">
'All he really did was just take some pictures\
with their equipment.'>
"- Hey, guess where we're going.\
- Do you know where Will is?">
'No, why?'>
'The Ariel meeting\
is pushed back till Wednesday.'>
'I just thought he was waiting around for it.\
Where are you going?'>
'What do they do with engineers\
when they turn 40?'>
'- What, Bradshaw?\
- Exactly. You know what?'>
"I do know where Will is.\
I'll let him know on my way out, OK?">
'- OK.\
- Thanks. Can you meet me out front?'>
'- Are you gonna drive?\
- OK, here. Take my keys.'>
'OK, if you can just pretend\
that this is the first time I came in.'>
'And if you would\
just tell him exactly what you told me...'>
'- OK, so what is it?\
- Protein build-up.'>
'(ABE) OK, can you just tell him?'>
'- Protein build-up.\
- (ABE) But what kind?'>
'Some fungus. Some fungus.'>
'Where did it come from?'>
"I don't know.\
You were supposed to take it to the lab.">
"Yeah, that's next.">
"- You were in design, weren't you?\
- Yeah.">
'How did you get over here?'>
'You know what they do\
with engineers when they turn 40?'>
'They take them out and shoot them.'>
"What the hell, Abe?\
You could've just shown me the pictures.">
'I want you to believe it.'>
'- Believe what, the protein? I believe you.\
- OK, look.'>
"This guy already thinks it's a joke, OK?\
So he may be a little defensive.">
'Really? Why would he think that?'>
'Please.'>
'Aspergillus ticor.'>
"This is a fungus that's everywhere.">
"It's in our bed, on our skin,\
sometimes even our GI tract. Everywhere.">
"It's basically the reason\
you don't leave things">
'in dark, damp, closed-off places.'>
'Thank you.'>
'Do you have that sample I brought?'>
'(ABE) There it is. Terger. T-E-R-G-E-R.'>
'OK, when I showed you this,\
tell him what you thought.'>
'You thought it was a joke, right?'>
'It is a joke.'>
'Right, but how did you know?'>
'Will you show him? Please?'>
'This is how I get protein A\
out of aspergillus ticor.'>
'We sweeten it, we agitate it,\
we spin it around, we sweeten some more.'>
'- Takes about a month.\
- To get the same amount I brought in.'>
'To get the same amount I brought in.'>
"(AARON) So if it's an incubator for fungus,\
is that valuable?">
"- That's not what it is.\
- Then what is it?">
"There's one other way it could secrete\
that much protein. It could do it naturally.">
'But that takes a lot longer.\
A lot longer.'>
"But if it has a little moisture\
and it's left alone,">
"it'll start secreting and it'll build up\
and build up, but it takes a long time.">
'- How long?\
- A long time.'>
'- More than a few days?\
- Yes.'>
'Then how long?'>
'He says to get the same amount of protein\
that we had,'>
'the same amount\
that I was wiping off every five days'>
'and five days later it would accumulate,'>
'he says it would take about\
five to six years.'>
'- I want to belittle this guy.\
- Exactly.'>
'So I said screw it,\
and I put my watch in there.'>
'- And?\
- I want you to do it.'>
'- Where is it? The box?\
- I took it back to the shop.'>
'- Wait, digital or old mechanical?\
- Exactly. I did both.'>
'- And what?\
- I want you to do it.'>
'(ABE) We thought that we were\
degrading gravity, right?'>
'That we were blocking that information.'>
"But I think we're doing more than that.\
I think we're blocking more than that.">
'Did you notice\
when you were controlling the feed,'>
'did you notice it was parabolic?'>
"OK, it's important.\
Parabolas are important. Here, look at this.">
"I don't know, Abe.">
"Now I'm going to start it up and let it run\
for 60 seconds with nothing in it, OK?">
"- It's empty this time.\
- That's 22...">
'In all the equations that describe motion\
and heat and entropy.'>
'Just one minute. Just a second.'>
"In all Feynman diagrams, what's the one\
variable that you can turn negative">
'and still get rational answers for?'>
"- One minute out here...\
- It's not mass, it's not...">
"- 22 hours, 27 minutes in the box.\
- It's odd, it's an odd number.">
"How many minutes is that?\
That's 1,347 minutes.">
'OK, yeah, 1,347, man,\
you got that fast.'>
"Why is it odd?\
How'd you know it was odd?">
"Because this is it, OK?\
This is what's going on.">
'There\'s an "A" end and there\'s a "B" end.'>
'Let\'s say the "A" end is 12:00\
and the "B" end is 12:01.'>
'All right? We start the machine\
with the weeble at the "A" end.'>
'- It travels forward...\
- You got to write this down.'>
"- Aaron, there's nothing to write down.\
- I'm writing it down.">
'Fine, it travels forward\
normally towards the "B" end,'>
'and when it gets there,\
the feed runs down parabolically'>
'until it should stop, but it doesn\'t.\
It curves back around towards the "A" end.'>
'When it gets back to the "A" end...\
Now, curve that around.'>
'OK, now the weeble has experienced\
a total of two minutes, and again it curves...'>
'(AARON) Back around. It curves parabolically.'>
'Right. So, it comes back around again,\
and it does this about 1,300 times,'>
'and when it finally exits on the "B" end,'>
"it's travelled an odd number\
of forward and backward trips.">
"Now, what is so special about 1,300?\
Why is it about 1,300? Why isn't it exact?">
'- This is not empirical.\
- Here, give me that.'>
"I don't know why it's not exact.\
There's some sort of probability there.">
'OK, every time it hits the "B" end\
there\'s a chance, OK?'>
'A small chance it won\'t\
curve back around towards the "A" end.'>
'And for some reason, it takes about\
1,300 trips before it finally does.'>
"But it does have to exit, or else we wouldn't\
be able to see it afterwards.">
"OK, let's take a look at this.">
'Yeah, 22 hours, 14 minutes.'>
'1,334 minutes.'>
'Even.'>
'Enter at the "B" end.'>
'Exit at the "B" end.'>
'(ABE) I just want you to see it\
the way I saw it.'>
'I am trying, OK? I really am, here.'>
"Look, everything we're putting in that box\
becomes ungrounded.">
"And I don't mean grounded like to the earth.\
I mean, not tethered.">
"We're blocking whatever keeps them\
moving forward, so they flip-flop.">
"Inside the box, it's like a street,\
and both ends are cul-de-sacs.">
"I mean, this isn't frame dragging\
or Wormhole matching.">
'- This is Basic Mechanics and Heat 101.\
- This is not mechanics and heat.'>
'We can publish.'>
'- Yeah, we can publish.\
- No, I mean we can really publish.'>
"Aaron, the weeble's stupid.\
It can't move.">
'I mean, even if we were\
to put the weeble in at point "B"'>
"it's still just going\
to bounce around back and forth,">
'until it gets kicked out at the "B" end.'>
'But if it were smart...'>
'it could enter at the "B" end\
and exit at the "A" end before it flips back.'>
"You're talking about making a bigger one.">
"You're talking about\
making a bigger one.">
"I... I didn't say anything.">
"You're the one talking about it.">
'So, you believe me?'>
"No, I don't.">
"- Come on. Let's go get a drink or something.\
- Yeah.">
"- (AARON) We're going to have to move it.\
- We will.">
'We need a box big enough\
for a person to fit into, right?'>
'As far as turning it on...'>
'(ABE) I was testing the box. It turns out\
that over half the rings are redundant.'>
'The inner ring is strong enough on its own,\
so it actually makes the plate smaller.'>
"- No.\
- And there's a lot more that's unnecessary.">
'Look, what we can do\
is take a lot of these small plates'>
'and surround a container\
with a web of them.'>
'How small?'>
'Well, I mean,\
it should be accumulative,'>
'So a lot of mini-fields\
equal one big one, right?'>
'Yeah, I mean, yeah.\
Sum of series, that makes sense.'>
'What I was going to say though, is we need\
to find some place where we can put it,'>
"and turn it on and it won't be disturbed.">
'- I mean some place...\
- We could just lock it in a closet.'>
'No, safer than a closet.'>
"Some place where someone's not going to go\
poking around and messing with it.">
'And climate-controlled.'>
"Yeah, yeah, so whatever,\
we'll find some place.">
'But I mean, so, if we go your route,\
with what, a bunch of mini-fields?'>
"That's a lot of work. We'd have to...\
I mean, how many days is that?">
'Abe, you know what we could use?\
You know what we could use?'>
'What?'>
"I know we've seen\
a lot of crazy things lately, OK?">
"And I know you're still trying to put it\
all together in a way that makes sense.">
"- But you got everything.\
- No, no, I don't.">
"Look, I just want you to understand\
that what's next is not a prank, OK?">
"I wouldn't do that to you,\
and I'm not doing that to you.">
"- So when you see this, you can't yell...\
- Did you bring one with you?">
'...or make any noise or run anywhere. OK?'>
"I know you probably feel\
like you're being tricked or made fun of.">
"But you're not, OK?\
I promise you. You're not.">
'OK?'>
'Who was that, Abe?'>
"Let's just wait.">
'Six minutes.'>
"Look, you sure you're OK to drive?">
'What did you do all day?\
The first time through?'>
'I spent the day\
in a hotel room in Russelfield.'>
"- Look, I'll just meet you back at the shop.\
- Wonder what I did.">
'- Guess I went back to work.\
- Yeah, probably.'>
'Probably just worked, I guess.'>
'Yeah, probably so.'>
'Look, now that I know about this, Abe...'>
'(PHONE RINGING)'>
"Don't do this again, OK?\
Not where it affects me.">
'Go ahead.'>
'Hi, Rachel.'>
'(AARON MUMBLING)'>
'(WATER RUNNING)'>
'Why not the lottery?'>
"Well, we can if you want,\
but it's not till Saturday.">
'But even if we win the full $10 million,'>
"it's only a couple of hundred thousand a year\
for, what, the next 30 years?">
'Only.'>
"- And that's just one good trade.\
- A couple of days like this.">
'That was just running a test.\
In and out.'>
'OK. Well, I want to do what you did.\
OK? Exactly what you did.'>
'(ABE) OK, the first thing I did\
is call in sick.'>
'- (AARON) OK, I did that.\
- And then I drove to the storage facility.'>
'OK, but I need to drop\
Lauren off at school first.'>
"OK, then meet me there.\
We're going to need both cars.">
'But we need to park yours way down\
the road, out of sight of the facility.'>
'- Wait, why are we doing that?\
- Because we need a ride home.'>
"- What is that...\
- No, it'll make sense.">
"OK, I'll be patient.">
'When I got to the storage room,\
I flooded the box with argon,'>
'and then I had to tighten it up\
to secure the leaks.'>
"- There's leaks?\
- There's always leaks.">
'At 8:30am I set the timer for 15 minutes,'>
'I jumped in the car,\
and drove to Russelfield.'>
'- OK, I lost it.\
- What?'>
'Why the timer?'>
'Because the moment\
we start those machines'>
"is the moment we'll end up\
getting out of them, and...">
'Right. Got it. Sorry.'>
"I don't want to be standing around\
when they do.">
'Yep.'>
'(ABE) While I was on the road at 8:45,\
the machine kicked on by itself, and...'>
'by 8:49 it was completely warmed up.'>
'In Russelfield I got a hotel room\
and tried to isolate myself.'>
'Wait, what do you mean, "isolate"?'>
'I mean, I closed the windows,\
I unplugged everything in the room,'>
'the telephone,\
TV, clock, radio, everything.'>
"I didn't want to take the chance\
of running into someone I knew,">
'or seeing something\
on the news that might...'>
"If we're dealing with causality,\
and I don't even know for sure...">
'- I just..\
- What?'>
'Took myself out of the equation.'>
'- (AARON) Err on the side of caution.\
- Yes.'>
'Well, then what did you do all clay?'>
'I just sat there.\
I mean, I had some books, but...'>
'(AARON) What? Were you nervous?'>
"Yeah. It's just mind-numbing,\
all the second-guessing.">
'Evacipate.'>
'At 2:30pm,\
I stopped by Williams Medical Supply,'>
'and picked up a class "E"\
oxygen tank and mask.'>
'I called my mutual fund company\
and asked which stock in their mid-cap fund'>
'had the greatest percentage gain that day.'>
'The idea was just to get enough information\
for one good trade.'>
'(AARON) When we go, can we just download\
chart data? Trade on each movement?'>
'Yeah, but if we do that,\
I want to use the library in Russelfield,'>
'use their computers.'>
'So, I got to the storage room at about 3:15,\
and out off the power to the box.'>
'It cycled down\
to a tolerable level at about 3:19.'>
'You see, the trick is to get in\
after it reaches a comfortable level,'>
"but before it shuts off completely.\
There's a window there.">
'So, does it hurt?'>
'Yeah. Yeah, it does a little.'>
"It's not bad, though,\
if you wait for the right time.">
"It's like a small static shock.\
Once you're in, you're fine, though.">
'What?'>
"(AARON) I know you've done it, OK?\
And I can only assume that you don't have">
'cancer or male impotence because of it.'>
'But I mean, what is your opinion\
on how safe this thing is?'>
'Aaron, I can imagine no way\
in which this thing would be considered'>
'anywhere remotely close to safe.'>
"All I know is I spent six hours in there,\
and I'm still alive.">
'You still want to do it?'>
'(METAL THUDDING)'>
'(MACHINE HUMMING)'>
'I set the alarm on my stopwatch\
for six hours.'>
'I regulated the O2 tank,\
took some Dramamine and tried to sleep.'>
'Did you?'>
'- What?\
- Did you sleep?'>
'Not at first.'>
"You know, I've never considered\
myself claustrophobic,">
"but I started sweating and I couldn't find\
the right flow rate on the tank,">
'and I was breathing a lot differently'>
'than I was when I was testing it\
on the outside.'>
'Eventually, I settled down, and...'>
"I don't know,\
maybe it was the Dramamine kicking in,">
'but I remember this moment in there,\
in the dark,'>
'with the reverberation of the machine.'>
"It was maybe the most content\
I've ever been.">
'I woke up on my own without the alarm\
and waited for the machine to cool down.'>
'Cool down from my perspective.'>
'It got to a point\
where it sounded safe to get out'>
'but the stopwatch still showed\
a couple minutes'>
'so I trusted the math and waited.'>
'(METAL THUDDING)'>
'(AARON SHIVERING)'>
'That is not a static shock, Abe.'>
'OK, please stop it.'>
'(ABE) You got out too soon.'>
'You have to wait for the stopwatch\
so that you know the gain is low enough.'>
"So, we're back here?">
"Yeah, we're here.\
It's 8:50, Tuesday morning.">
'All right. Give me a few minutes.'>
'(ABE) From there it was easy.\
The bulk of the work was done.'>
'I just left everything the way I found it.'>
"I left the machine alone\
and didn't turn it off or anything,">
'and just cleared out of there.'>
'(AARON) OK, so that way,\
your double would find everything'>
'exactly the same later that day\
and get in the box?'>
'Right, right, but also, at that point,\
I or my double or someone'>
'was in the box coming backwards.'>
"So who knows what that would've done\
if I would have turned the machine off.">
"(AARON) Definitely. Definitely.\
So, they're one-time use only.">
'So then, at that moment, since my double\
was on the way to the hotel room in my car,'>
"I had to take a taxi home. But when we go,\
we'll be able to use your truck.">
'- You have a margin account, right?\
- Yeah. I do now. What are we buying?'>
"Good. Today, before 12:30, we're going\
to buy as many shares as we can of RGWU.">
"Then they'll announce\
that their earnings for the quarter">
'are three-and-a-half times consensus,'>
'and the stock will nearly double\
in afternoon trading.'>
'- What do they do?\
- What do you mean?'>
'What does... What does this company do?\
Do they make things or...'>
"I don't know. It doesn't matter.\
All that matters is that the price goes up.">
"And the volume is so high\
that the number of shares we're trading">
'is not going to affect the price.'>
"You really don't know what they do?">
'(COMPUTER KEYS CLACKING)'>
"That's why you were talking\
about a mid-cap fund,">
'so the volume\
would be high enough to hide us.'>
"- Do you think that's too cautious?\
- I don't know.">
"I know there's\
a lot of other stocks out there">
'that do a lot more than double,\
but this is my first day.'>
'(ABE) My God.'>
"- (AARON) She's not getting paid, already.\
- (KARA) I know, Abe.">
"- (AARON) This is what she does.\
- That's the question.">
"(ABE) I know, so what's the answer?\
I mean, you've got the $400 billion,">
"you've gone the charity route,">
'you have this perfect 100-room mansion'>
'with matching his and her yachts\
and helicopter pads.'>
'I mean, basically, you have absolute impunity\
to do whatever you want.'>
'- Nobody can touch you.\
- Yeah.'>
"- You're fresh back from this two-year...\
- Above the law.">
'Well, absolutely, well above.'>
"You're fresh back\
from this two-year world-galloping vacation.">
"- How do you fill your day? What do you do?\
- Abe, I know that's the question,">
"but it's not a real question,\
so why does it matter?">
"(ABE) So what's the answer?">
"Babe, he knows that's the question, OK?\
He's asking you the question.">
'Well, what do you mean?\
What would I do with my life'>
'- or what would I do tomorrow?\
- My God, either.'>
'Well...'>
"I'd have to do something constructive.\
I'd have to do something that would help.">
"- Something to make you feel good.\
- I know. That's fantastic. Good.">
'My wife. So good.\
So pure. You are pure.'>
'- (KARA) Shut up. Why did you ask, then?\
- This is what I would do.'>
"I would wake up tomorrow morning\
and I'd go over to Gabriel Capital Inc.">
"And I would tell Joseph Platts' receptionist\
that I'm there to see him.">
'And when he comes out,'>
'I would ram my fist\
through the flat of his nose.'>
'Just one good punch, one good pow.'>
"- That's amazing. It's about time.\
- That's so great.">
"Where did this come from? You're the one\
that's always defending the guy.">
"- It's only natural.\
- I'd only do it though if I knew that">
'you know, no one would find out\
or get hurt or anything.'>
'Like, I wish that there was a way\
that I could do it,'>
'and, uh, go back and tell myself not to.'>
"Cos I just want to know what it feels like.\
That's all, really.">
"I'm so proud.">
'Finally, my husband, the hero.'>
"You can't do that.">
'- I know.\
- Did you call pest control?'>
"Babe, they're birds.">
"You don't want a bunch\
of dead baby birds up there, do you?">
"They don't sound like birds.">
'She thinks there are rats in the attic.'>
'(MAN) But the idea had been spoken,'>
"and the words wouldn't go back\
after they'd been uttered aloud.">
"So you're understanding this, right?">
"Look, Abe, you don't have to sell me\
on not doing this, OK?">
"I don't really think I told you...">
'The thing is, even if you do stop yourself,\
your double, from hitting Platts,'>
'then why would he, your double,\
get back in the box?'>
'(MAN) And with no need for it,\
no possible real-world application,'>
'no advantage at all to be gained from it,\
the idea stayed.'>
'How would you do it?'>
"I wouldn't.">
"- Just for fun.\
- I still wouldn't.">
'- But what if there was a way to...\
- Look, Abe, look.'>
"I'm not going to pretend like I know\
anything about paradoxes, you know?">
"Or what follows them. And honestly,\
I really don't believe in any of that crap.">
'I mean, kill your mom\
before you were born, whatever.'>
'It has to work itself out somehow.'>
"- I don't know, man.\
- Look, this is what I know for sure, OK?">
'About the worst thing in the world'>
"is to know that the moment you're\
experiencing has already been defined,">
'that this is the second or third time through,\
or whatever, and...'>
'do you ever feel, you know, like...'>
"I don't know, maybe things aren't right,\
like maybe your life is in disarray">
'or just not what you would like\
and you start to wonder, you know,'>
'"What caused this?\
How did things get like this?"'>
'You know, people are always\
blaming their parents, you know,'>
'as if their mom would have breastfed them,\
their lives would have turned out different.'>
"- Bunch of whiners.\
- Yeah, they're a bunch of whiners.">
"But what if it wasn't\
something you wondered about.">
'What if you knew for sure this is not the way\
things are supposed to be.'>
"I'm not like that.">
'I\'m not into the whole\
"destiny, there\'s-only-one-right-way" thing.'>
"Abe, I'm not, either, OK?\
But what's worse?">
"You know, thinking you're being paranoid\
or knowing you should be?">
"You don't have to look at me like that.\
I'm OK.">
'(ABE) No, I just assumed that you would.\
I mean, I trust her.'>
'I know that when I decided to tell you...'>
'- Not that I was ever thinking of not...\
- Decided to tell me? Thank you.'>
"I just knew that you're married\
and that there's no secrets,">
"and anything I tell you, she'll know.">
"- It's not a matter of trust.\
- No, I know.">
"It's just how much better will it be\
if in a few days, you know,">
'I surprise her and we all just fly to Costa Rica\
or somewhere for a month?'>
"You know,\
we'll let her understand it gradually.">
'- Maybe do some real estate shopping...\
- For now, though, if you wanted to,'>
'you can just tell her\
you had a good day in the market.'>
"You don't understand. No.">
"You don't understand the questions\
that come with that, OK?">
"But we'll explain it to her,">
"and we'll all just take some time\
to figure out what's next,">
'which, right away I think,\
should be building a bigger box,'>
'like the size of a room or something,'>
'at least more than one person\
could fit into it.'>
'Safe or not,\
the thing feels like a coffin the way it is.'>
'By the way, this is our guy.'>
"What's the volume?">
'Five-and-a-half.'>
"What's the return? Holy...">
"Yeah. No, I can't beat that.">
'But mainly, I guess I was just talking\
about Robert and Phillip, you know.'>
"I don't want to tell them.">
'I know they have a lot invested\
in the group, and I just...'>
"I don't want to tell them.">
'Abe, if you need me\
to take the guilt on this one, fine.'>
"OK? I accept it gladly. It's mine.">
'At the end of this week,\
they can have whatever they want, OK?'>
"I'll turn over patent rights\
on everything from the last two years.">
'They can have the equipment,\
the garage, the house.'>
'They can have my truck\
if that makes you feel better, OK?'>
"But I am not telling them a thing about this.\
We're not.">
'(AARON) God,\
everything is so different in there.'>
'You can feel how cut off you are,\
you know.'>
"It's this entirely separate world\
and you encompass most of it.">
"(ABE) And the sound.\
Isn't the sound different on the inside?">
"It's like it's singing.\
I guess you can't hear it on the outside...">
'I had this dream in there.'>
'- About what?\
- (SIGHS)'>
'I was on or near the ocean,\
and I just kept hearing the surf.'>
'It was so uneventful.'>
'At night.\
And the tide kept coming in and out.'>
'- Yeah.\
- Yeah.'>
"Hey, whoa, come here for a second, man.\
What's on your hand?">
'- Are you bleeding?\
- That is blood.'>
'- Turn around.\
- You see it?'>
"- Where is it coming from?\
- It's your notebook.">
"- Aaron, it's you.\
- What is this?">
"My gosh, it's on your ear.\
Your ear's bleeding. Man.">
'Give me that. I got it.'>
"- Is that normal? This isn't normal.\
- For the machine?">
"No, for people.\
You think it's the machine?">
'I got it.'>
'Great. We can actually\
get some work done today.'>
"Hi, guys. What's going on?">
"I always seem to get a lot more done\
when I'm not locked out.">
'(ABE) Yeah.\
He said they had to spray again.'>
"Yeah. But he can't tell us about it\
in advance. ls hero even here?">
'Besides, you never see anything\
around here but those geckos, anyway.'>
"- Oh, I know.\
- Yeah, I think it's for the geckos.">
'- (BOTH) What?\
- (PHILLIP) Why?'>
'(ROBERT) Oh, hey, man,\
thanks for the present.'>
'Yeah... yeah,\
how is that working out for you?'>
'You know what?\
You guys, both of you,'>
'- you make fun, but there is a difference.\
- Wait. What did you call him?'>
'- What?\
- When you walked in? What did you say?'>
"- He really didn't tell you about it?\
- No.">
"All right. Rachel's ex-boyfriend\
walks into my birthday party with a shotgun.">
'- What?\
- Swear to God.'>
"(AARON) Yeah, Abe.\
I've already gotten that speech from Kara.">
"You're going to get it from me.\
You have a wife and kid.">
"It's funny how you two are the only people\
who have a problem with it.">
"- Everybody else thinks I did a good thing.\
- Well, you didn't.">
"You can't go risking your life and especially\
the welfare of Kara and Lauren">
'for someone like Rachel.'>
'She practically begged\
for this to happen to her.'>
"I figured at least you'd understand this.">
"Understand what?\
You've never been like this.">
"That's what I mean. You see...">
'You see how different things are now.'>
'Different?\
How are things different?'>
'You see it, OK? I know you do.'>
'Look, that was the night you had told me\
everything about the machine, OK?'>
'And everything you told me\
was so fresh in my head,'>
'and when I saw this guy,'>
"you know, I'm looking at him.\
I wasn't going to let him do that.">
"I wasn't going to let him\
scare people like that. And I...">
'I know it was stupid, OK?'>
"But, I mean, this whole idea,\
this whole thing that we're doing...">
"it just took some getting used to for me.\
I wasn't completely acclimated to it.">
'OK. If it was just you\
you had to worry about,'>
"you know, I'd still think you're stupid.\
But now, you have a family now.">
'And God, especially now,\
to risk anything would be completely crazy.'>
'I know, OK?'>
"And the thing is,\
I know you know that, but you've got to...">
'I know, OK? I know.'>
'Filby!'>
"You little sack of... You know what?\
Even if you see him, don't tell me.">
"It's not my fault if I don't know.\
I just hope the thing runs away.">
'Then what are we doing out here?'>
"She worries about the cat,\
so you look for the cat. It's what you do.">
"- I don't know.\
- What do you mean?">
"It's just a little embarrassing.">
'The storage room guy sees us\
come in together but he never sees us leave.'>
'Yeah, but what do you think\
the receptionist thinks'>
'about two guys that come and get a room\
for six hours every day?'>
'(PHONE RINGING)'>
'Did you unplug this?'>
'(PHONE KEEPS RINGING)'>
'You brought your cell phone?'>
'Can I check the caller ID?'>
"Yeah, we're not... We're not back.">
"Yeah. Yeah,\
but you can't take it back with you, OK?">
'This is Aaron. Hey, babe.'>
"Yeah, I'm not there. I had to come downtown\
and hold some of these guys' hands.">
'Tell me.'>
'(SIGHS) That sounds good.'>
"No, I've got to eat with these off site fags.">
"Save mine, though.\
I'll have it later.">
'OK.'>
'Yeah. Um... yeah, 6:00.'>
'(CHEERING ON TV)'>
'(MAN TALKING ON TV)'>
'What?'>
"- What?\
- We're supposed to win this by two.">
'They just turned over\
with the 12 on the clock.'>
'We have to foul.'>
'- No.\
- No, we have to foul.'>
'What? No, we foul here,'>
"they miss the first free throw,\
they come back with a three, that's right.">
"That's right.">
'Yeah.'>
"Man, are you hungry?\
I haven't eaten since later this afternoon.">
"What's up, you guys?">
'(PHONE RINGING)'>
"- You have to be kidding me.\
- I'm sorry.">
"I'm sorry,\
I forgot it was in my pocket.">
"- It's Kara.\
- Yeah.">
'How do cell phones work?'>
"If there's two duplicate phones\
and I call the same number,">
'do they both ring at the same time,\
or is there...'>
"- That's not how they work.\
- They both ring. It's a radio signal.">
"No, it's a network.">
'The network checks each area.\
When it finds the phone, it stops ringing.'>
'It only... It rings the first one.'>
"This one's ringing.">
'Right.'>
"So the one your double has\
in Russelfield can't be.">
'Right. I think we broke symmetry.'>
"- Are you sure that's how cell phones work?\
- No.">
'You feel all right?'>
'- I feel fine. Do you?\
- Yeah.'>
'(CAR ALARM BLARING)'>
'(CAR HORN HONKING)'>
'- (ABE) Is Kara asleep? Did I wake you up?\
- Yeah.'>
'No, not me,\
it felt more like a nap.'>
"I think my body's getting used\
to these 36-hour days.">
"What's going on?">
'We can do this, but we have to do it now.\
Do you have his home address?'>
'Why now?'>
'We were planning on taking a trip tomorrow,\
right? Just like today?'>
'- Yeah, for stocks.\
- OK, well...'>
'Half an hour ago I was asleep.\
This car alarm woke me up.'>
'These kids were down skating by,\
hitting every car on the block.'>
"So we go right now, do our business\
at the Platts', get back in the box,">
'and come back to right before\
those kids are setting off the alarms.'>
"All we'd really have to do is stand there\
in plain sight to scare them off.">
'So that way my double\
sleeps through the night,'>
"they don't have\
the conversation we're having now,">
'and they get in the box tomorrow as usual.'>
"- Yeah. They'll be changed. But...\
- Yeah, but at least they'll get in the box.">
"Wait, how do we go back that far\
if the machines haven't been running?">
'Have they been running?'>
"Yeah. I started going by at five o'clock\
and turning them on, 5:00pm.">
'I just got tired of the whole\
unanswerable question...'>
'Are we doing this as an experiment,\
or are we doing this for me?'>
"- A little of both.\
- Five o'clock.">
"If we get this done by 3:00,\
that's ten hours in the box.">
"I've got the O2 tanks in the car.">
"It's going to be a long day.">
"- Is that...\
- Is that Rachel's car?">
"No, that's not Rachel's, that's her dad's.\
They have the same kind.">
'Did you see that?'>
"That's Mr... That's Mr Granger.\
That's Thomas. He's sitting in that car.">
'What?'>
'I swear that was him.\
What the hell is he doing...'>
'just sitting outside my house\
at 2:00 in the morning?'>
"I don't believe this.\
What, is he following us?">
'Abe, what are you doing?'>
"- What are you doing?\
- Let's just see what he wants.">
"No, let's just get out\
of my neighbourhood first.">
'- But why?\
- Come on.'>
'- Did you see him today?\
- No.'>
'I did. I saw him this afternoon.\
Around 6:00.'>
"You sure you didn't see him\
when we drove past?">
'No, what?'>
"I'm almost positive this afternoon\
he was clean-shaven. In fact, I know he was.">
'He was ready to go to some function\
with his wife.'>
"He looks like he's got, like,\
a two or three-day growth now.">
"- Are you sure?\
- No, I'm not sure, but I think so.">
'Hey, Rachel. Hey, this is Abe.\
Did I wake you up?'>
"Yeah, hey, can I get your dad's number\
from you real quick?">
'Yeah. OK, go ahead.'>
"- All right, yeah, thanks.\
- Wait, what's he doing?">
"He's just sitting there.">
"He got out for a second and I don't know,\
I thought he was coming over,">
"and then he got back in the car.\
I think he's drunk.">
'Hi. Sorry to call so late.'>
'May I speak to Thomas Granger,\
please?'>
'Yeah, this is James Miller\
from Putney and Myers.'>
'Hi, Mr Granger?'>
'Thomas Granger?'>
'Hey! Hey! What are you doing here?\
Come here!'>
'(DOG BARKING)'>
'What happened?'>
"I'm OK. I slipped.">
'(DOOR OPENING)'>
'I just want to know what box he used.\
You built one for you, right? Just the one?'>
'Yeah. How many do you think I made?'>
'And these are set right.\
I turned them on at 5:00.'>
'He could have used one\
and gone back to 5:00.'>
'He could be in one of them right now.'>
"I say we shut them off\
and see if he's in there.">
'Were you planning on talking to him?'>
"Just tell me if you were.\
I'm not going to be mad, just tell me.">
"No, I promise you. You know I wouldn't.\
Are you sure you wouldn't?">
"You're the one that can't get near\
without passing out.">
'There is no way\
I would tell anyone about this. No way.'>
"- Can you think of any reason you might?\
- No, I can't.">
"Sometimes we do things,\
but don't know how we got to that point.">
"- No, I can't.\
- Can't what?">
"I can't think of any reason why I would.">
"I can't either.">
'What if it was an emergency?'>
"- So you'd do it if it was an emergency?\
- No, I don't know. What, so you might, then?">
"I don't know.\
What kind of emergency?">
'(MAN) The permutations were endless.'>
'- (PHONE RINGS)\
- OK, go ahead.'>
'They tried again going to the source,'>
'but even while keeping him separated\
from Abe by two rooms...'>
'Ask him his name.'>
"...Thomas Granger's condition\
could only be described as vegetative.">
'What did he say?'>
'From this they deduced\
that the problem was recursive,'>
'but beyond that, found themselves admitting,\
against their own nature,'>
'and once again,\
that the answer was unknowable.'>
'What do you think he changed?'>
"It couldn't have been much.\
We didn't have any contact with him">
"in the three hours\
he could've done anything.">
'I know he changed this.'>
"I know we weren't having\
this conversation the first time through.">
"- So you don't know what we lost.\
- Really, it could not have been much.">
"It doesn't matter how much.\
It just matters that it's changed.">
"- Look, Abe, I know what you're saying, OK?\
- (MAN) The question should have been">
'what to do with the comatose man\
in the guest bedroom.'>
'We can wait this out.'>
"But in Abe's mind,\
he was already compiling the list.">
'Two milligrams of oral triazolam\
every seven hours'>
'induces a safe sleep state\
and a minimal metabolic rate.'>
'At this continued state of rest,'>
'the human body breathes\
0.3 litres of oxygen a minute,'>
'or roughly 2,000 litres in four days.'>
'A class E oxygen tank holds 625 litres.'>
'To maintain hydration,'>
'the body cycles through a minimum\
of two-and-a-half litres of water per day.'>
'Any food would be a luxury,'>
'but the small tank\
of medical-grade nitrous oxide'>
'would be needed on the other side.'>
'Past the room that contained their machines,\
and up two levels,'>
'he made his way to another room'>
'where he had stored\
what I will refer to from here on'>
'as the failsafe machine.'>
'(GAS HISSING)'>
"There he is.\
I've been calling you all morning.">
'Really?'>
'Your cell and work.'>
"- I'm not there.\
- Really?">
"I don't even know. What?">
"I'm just tired.">
"I hope you're not implying\
that any day is unimportant at Cortex Semi.">
'(ABE) I was going to come\
give you this big speech'>
"about how we've been friends for a long time\
and built up trust, and that whole thing.">
'But how about this instead?'>
'If you ditch work this afternoon and promise\
to do the few small things that I ask you,'>
'I will in return show you\
the most important thing'>
'that any living organism\
has ever witnessed.'>
'(MAN) At this point there would\
have been some discussion.'>
'Abe would, of course,\
want to know how.'>
'Aaron would have to explain\
all about the storage manifest'>
'and how it showed two rooms\
under the name Abram Terger.'>
'Then Abe would need to know how.'>
'Aaron would explain\
that when he went up there'>
'and found the failsafe running,'>
'he knew exactly what it was.'>
'But Abe would ask, "How?"'>
'And then the bit\
about the modular design of the coffins,'>
'and how it meant he could fold one up\
and take it back inside another.'>
'They are not one-time use only.\
They are recyclable, Aaron would say.'>
'"How?" Abe would ask.'>
'And Aaron would describe\
how simple things become'>
'when you know precisely\
what someone will have for breakfast'>
'even in a world of tamper-proof lids.'>
'How?'>
"And that's where\
I would have entered the story.">
'Or exited, depending on your reference.'>
"Because when Aaron came back\
the second time, it wasn't so easy.">
"He wasn't expecting me\
to put up a fight,">
'and by that time\
he was too exhausted to take me.'>
'But for reasons\
that are only evident to me now,'>
'I understood that he simply wanted it more.\
That he just had more invested.'>
'So I left.'>
'He had already performed the task,\
as I had intended to,'>
'of recording the conversations of the day,\
just in case.'>
'Through that earpiece\
he had a three-second lead on the world.'>
'Aaron, you need some sleep.\
Some real sleep.'>
"I can't. I've got a schedule.">
'He had but to speak aloud the words\
that came into his head,'>
'and those around him would fall in line.'>
'(AARON ON EARPIECE) This is track 3.'>
"Abe is bringing my car around\
and I'm on my way to the court.">
"I'll see Will there.">
"I'll invite him to the party and make sure\
he's bringing Rachel's boyfriend.">
"- 'Hey, Will.'\
- 'Hey.">
'- (AARON) Will, hey.\
- (WILL) You pretentious prick!'>
'You pretentious prick.\
What the hell is that? Your cell phone?'>
"- No, it's a radio.\
- 'You look like secret service.">
'- You look like secret service.\
- Ariel meeting is moved to Wednesday.'>
'What? What the hell\
am I hanging around here for?'>
"- Yeah, I know. I'm sorry.\
- (WILL) Nice shot, Aaron.">
'Prick. That is ugly, Aaron.'>
'(WILL) We could have used\
that last week against TI.'>
"(WILL) At least you've got\
your golf game, right?">
"I see you've been practising.">
'You come out here with your $3-tie\
and think you can play white ball.'>
"- Don't worry, I'm not going to tell anyone.\
- (AARON) What are you doing tonight?">
'Hey. What are you doing tonight?'>
'I was supposed to be in Raleigh,\
but thanks to you guys I missed my flight.'>
'- You know Robert?\
- Yeah.'>
"He's got a birthday tonight.\
Why don't you come out?">
"- I'm just going to hang out with my cousin.\
- Bring him. Rachel will be there.">
'- Oh, big reunion.\
- Exactly.'>
'That should be fun.'>
"I don't think I'm doing this.">
'Why not?'>
'Because I can think of about a million\
different ways that this can happen'>
'and nobody comes anywhere near\
getting hurt.'>
'I can call her and see\
if she wants to do something else'>
"or better yet, not even talk to her at all,\
and she won't even know about the party.">
"That's good for tonight.\
What about tomorrow?">
"- And every other day?\
- I'll take care of tomorrow, tomorrow.">
"Yeah, you'll watch her all the time.">
'This guy is crazy enough\
to walk into a roomful of people'>
'waving a shotgun around.'>
"What do you think he's going to do\
if he ever finds her alone?">
'This way we know exactly what happens.\
We have complete control over it.'>
'At the end of the night,\
this guy is arrested and goes to jail.'>
"That's the way it goes.\
Your words, not mine.">
'Now come on. It has to be you.'>
'She said she was there because\
you told her you would be there.'>
"Don't tell me I came back\
and did this for nothing.">
"He doesn't fire?">
"- No. He didn't fire.\
- Not even when you rushed him?">
"No, he didn't the time I wasn't there.">
"He didn't the time I was,\
when I rushed him.">
"And from what Robert tells you,\
he didn't do it tonight.">
"He doesn't have the nerve. I mean the guy...\
We know everything.">
"OK? We're prescient.">
'We can still be careful.'>
'Maybe we can get to the gun\
without him knowing.'>
'We definitely can.\
He leaves it in the truck before he goes in.'>
"I mean, we don't even need to,\
but if it makes you feel better...">
"What's wrong with our hands?">
'What do you mean?'>
"Why can't we write like normal people?">
"I don't know.\
I can see the letters.">
"I know what they should look like.\
I just can't get my hand to make them easily.">
'Try comparing it to your left hand.\
That looks the same.'>
'(PHONE RINGING)'>
'Hey, Rachel.'>
'Yeah, yeah.'>
'Hey, guess what today is?'>
"No, no.\
It's your friend Robert's birthday.">
'He says he likes records,\
so I got him "The Best of Bread".'>
'No, no, real records, like vinyl.'>
'(MAN) I can tell you with certainty\
what I did that night when it was my turn.'>
'But I think it would do little good,\
because what the world remembers'>
'the actuality, the last revision,\
is what counts, apparently.'>
'So how many times did it take Aaron'>
'as he cycled through\
the same conversations'>
'lip-synching trivia over and over?'>
'How many times would it take\
before he got it right?'>
'Three? Four?'>
'Twenty?'>
"I've decided to believe that only one more\
would have done it.">
"I can almost sleep at night\
if there's only one more.">
'Slowly and methodically\
he reverse-engineered a perfect moment.'>
'He took from his surroundings what\
was needed and made of it something more.'>
'And once the details\
had been successfully navigated,'>
'there would be nothing left to do\
but wait for the conflict.'>
'Maybe the obligatory\
last-minute moral debate'>
'until the noise of the room\
escalates into panic'>
'and background screams\
as the gunman walks in.'>
'And eventually he must have got it perfect,\
and it must have been beautiful'>
'with all the praise and adoration\
he had coming.'>
'He had probably saved lives, after all.'>
"Who knows what would have happened\
if he hadn't been there?">
'(AARON) Look...'>
'I know that things are bad, OK?'>
"I know that you don't agree\
with what I've done.">
"I know that you're upset,">
"and to be honest I'm not too happy\
with you, either, right now.">
"But you know that this is going to pass.\
So let's just go.">
"Let's get out there. Let's go somewhere\
where we don't speak the language.">
"Aaron, we don't have\
the money back here">
"and we'd have to steal\
our own passports.">
"Money? We'll make money.">
'They have sports betting in Vegas.\
March madness?'>
"We'll make enough in one night\
to finance a thousand vacations.">
"- Passports.\
- You know they're not using theirs anyways.">
'(BANGING)'>
"Now, come on. I'm thinking Star City.\
Check out the cosmonaut training grounds.">
'(BANGING ON DOOR)'>
"I'm staying here.">
'Why?'>
'(BANGING CONTINUES)'>
"(AARON) They'll be building\
their own boxes in another day.">
"And yours already knows\
what they've built.">
"You're not going to be able\
to watch them forever.">
"(ABE) The box Abe is building\
won't work.">
"He's got it wired wrong.">
"And if they fix that,\
I'll start actually taking pieces out of it.">
"It's just a gimmick.\
It doesn't work anymore.">
'And your double will say\
they have to move on to something else.'>
"- And mine will agree. They're friends.\
- You're staying? Why?">
"Why? Let's see,\
why would Abe stay?">
'What possible reason\
could there be to be here?'>
"I guess that it just won't\
go back far enough, will it?">
"Tell you what,\
why don't you take Kara and Lauren">
'and put them in the box,\
and then you and Aaron can each keep a set'>
"and you'll both have families\
and you can stop feeding off it.">
"- They'll come back.\
- You can each keep a set in a hemisphere.">
"And I don't think there's ever been\
any reason to show you what I'm capable of">
"but I'm telling you this now.">
'Go out there\
and do whatever the hell you want.'>
"There's no way in the world\
I can stop you.">
"But don't come back here,\
and don't come near them.">
'Any of them.'>
'(MAN) Now I have repaid any debt\
I may have owed you.'>
'You know all that I know.'>
'My voice is the only proof\
that you will have of the truth of any of this.'>
'I might have written a letter\
with my signature,'>
'but my handwriting\
is not what it used to be.'>
'(SPEAKING FRENCH)'>
"Maybe you've had the presence of mind\
to record this.">
"That's your prerogative.">
'You will not be contacted by me again.'>
'Good morning.'>
'Every half metre.'>
'(SPEAKING FRENCH)'>
'Everywhere.'>
'And if you look, you will not find me.'>