(PHONE RINGING)
(MAN) Here's what's going to happen.
I'm gonna read this,
and you're gonna listen,
and you're gonna stay on the line,
and you're not gonna interrupt.
You're not gonna speak for any reason.
Some of this you know.
I'm gonna start
at the top of the page.
Meticulous, yes.
Methodical. Educated.
They were these things.
Nothing extreme.
Like anyone, they varied.
There were days of mistakes
and laziness and infighting.
And there were days, good days,
when by anyone's judgement
they would have to be considered clever.
No one would say
that what they were doing was complicated.
It wouldn't even be considered new,
except for maybe in the geological sense.
They took from their surroundings
what was needed,
and made of it something more.
- I extended that.
- Wait, what order date you put on this?
- (PHILLIP) The 28th. Why? What do you care?
- (ROBERT) I don't know...
- Yeah, I'm putting the 28th.
- Have you...
Have you thought any more
about what you want to put forward?
- Uh, not really.
- Because I was...
I mean, I haven't changed my mind
or anything.
Phillip and I were talking.
We think it'd be good. It'd be fun.
Look, nobody's saying it wouldn't be fun.
It's just, the time for jacking around
with Tesla coils
and ball lightning in the garage is over.
Maybe this is something you should try
on your own, in your free time, you know?
My free time? Which free time?
Free time after the 50 hours at work,
after the 30 hours
I already spend in that garage?
- We're all working the same schedule.
- (PHONE RINGING)
And it's not a Tesla coil.
I guess I could shave a couple of minutes
off my day by eating on the toilet.
Look, how many patents do we have?
In the last 14 months?
- Did you sign the agreement?
- Nobody signed the agreement.
It doesn't matter,
we're sticking to the agreement.
(ABE) Name one other thing that's come
out of that garage that's remotely profitable.
If you're talking about...
I don't see anybody quitting
their jobs because of it.
I know I'm not. Are you?
(AARON) I think Abe just means
that right now the JTAG cards are it.
And when you look
at the addresses on these things,
we have a lot of apartments,
a lot of residences.
But these are not the bulk orders
to OEMs or retail giants.
- These are the quiet basement...
- (ROBERT) Hackers.
Yeah, hacker wannabes
testing their dads' old motherboards.
And I know that a lot of that is my fault,
admittedly, you know.
With everything last year, and...
the doubletalk we were getting from Platts
and all the stuff
we're not going to get into now...
(PHILLIP) Maybe we should get into it.
I'm sorry. What?
(ROBERT) Go ahead. Tell him.
Maybe we should get into it.
I talked to my brother today.
He knows of at least two other cases.
We should at least let Platts know
we're talking about it.
Forget Platts.
This has got to start being about
what has the best chance of going to market,
and what is going to get us
that VC attention.
Look, I stuck by you guys
when it was your turn,
when I wasn't 100% sure
of what we were doing,
or even if I didn't agree, maybe.
(WATER RUNNING)
But if it's my turn,
if we're still playing by the rules,
then this is what I want to try.
(CROCKERY CLATTERING)
- (KARA) Here, take it.
- No, really.
Oh, Robert, please.
It's not going to hold.
- (ROBERT) It's going to go bad in my car.
- It'll go bad here. OK, thanks.
- Good night, y'all.
- See you.
We just got done
giving this huge speech about this.
- What, we gave a speech?
- We just got done. It was five minutes ago.
No, I gave a speech.
I'm the one who forced the issue, remember?
And in fact, you know, they're onto us
because I suck as a bad cop.
- I don't know about that.
- You should do it. You could fake it better.
I don't know about that either.
Look, as long as we're going down this road
where it's eighth-grade physics,
and happy fun time out in that garage,
I think we could stand to try this.
You know, Phillip and Robert
are gung-ho on theirs, and that's fine.
But you know I have no interest in that.
And I know you have no interest in that,
besides the fact that Phillip and Robert
don't even need us for what they want to do.
They just want to use the equipment.
For what I want to do?
We don't need them.
Not even Phillip,
cos it doesn't need software.
- Is she asleep?
- No, and she needs a bath.
She's gonna wind up
in the closet if I do it.
That's fine.
You know, even if Robert's OK with it,
and he won't be,
I don't even think I understand
what we're saying the thing's going to do.
I think we should let them go at it
for the next two months.
You know, they do theirs, we do ours.
(KARA) They said it'd take 14 hours
from the time we installed it.
Don't eat that.
Don't eat that. Seriously, it's bad.
We have to throw the first
couple of batches out. The filter.
What about crushed?
- (ROBERT) These guys are funded.
- These guys are... What?
- Liquid helium. These guys are funded.
- No, that's what this is, OK?
That's the whole difference.
That's what the box is.
This way we don't have to play
the game where we're going back and forth
coming up with new and innovative ways
to make the thing colder,
- and generally unusable in the process.
- (PHILLIP) Aaron, I need the hexagonal set.
- And unmarketable.
- Right, and unmarketable.
By coming at it from the back end,
see, rather than changing
the surrounding temperature,
we'll just change the level that it'll conduct,
the transition temperature.
And, see, by bombarding these edges...
What he's saying is, these guys,
they're dropping the ceramic,
the temperature lower and lower.
It makes the ceramic less resistant,
knocks out the interior magnetic field.
Exactly. What he's saying is...
What I'm saying is,
we drop the box down on it.
OK? Focus our own magnetic field to negate,
knock out with the inverse
- what's going on inside the ceramic.
- It's smart.
And that should change
the transition temperature
to something we can work with.
- What are we saying that is?
- Hopefully, near room temperature.
What is that about
the best mathematician is a lazy one?
- What did you ask for?
- (PHILLIP) I asked. I need the hexagonal set.
- What did you call it?
- (PHILLIP) Just come on.
- Are these Type One?
- The superconductors?
- (BOTH) Yeah, they're Type One.
- What? Is that going to be a problem?
There's plenty lying around at work,
but they're all bar-coded, so...
- if I have to buy the kits, I'll buy the kits.
- What are you doing about the source?
What?
- I can get them.
- You can... Are you sure?
I thought you didn't like this idea anyways.
If you gotta buy 'em, you gotta buy 'em,
but everything else we can take care of.
What are you doing about the source here?
You know that story
about how NASA spent millions of dollars
developing this pen that writes in zero-G?
- Did you ever read that?
- Yeah.
- And how Russia solved the problem?
- Yeah, they used a pencil.
Right, a normal wooden pencil.
It just seems like Phillip takes
the NASA route almost every time.
- It's a palladium, right?
- You got their diagram, what does it say?
They use a ratio of both,
platinum and palladium.
But I don't know if that's necessary.
I think they're just showing off.
If you have it, you gotta use it, right?
I want to get a replacement router.
- I'm putting down four ounces of palladium.
- (AARON) Did Robert look at it?
- Yeah, I already got his eye.
- (ROBERT) I can't fix it.
- OK. Where are you getting it?
- Wal-Mart. It's like $50.
- OK. Can you get a receipt, please?
- Yeah.
Platinum or palladium is less resistant?
- Abe.
- Just, it's not a...
Yeah, I don't care.
So resistance doesn't matter.
I need an aye or a yes.
- Did you jiggle the...
- Collet nut? Yeah.
- Flip the...
- Robert did it.
Well, yes. Yeah, I guess. Aye.
Well, then, which is cheaper?
You're not going to buy it, are you?
Well, unless you've got
a few grams of palladium lying around.
What?
I'm just saying, why would they put it in there
if you didn't need it?
One catalytic converter. It's fine.
Just remember to put it back, OK?
Your emissions went up 300%.
- Is there enough in here?
- Yeah, should be.
If not, we'll pull the one
out of my truck.
OK, copper tubing.
- This will be out of commission, right?
- Without the tubing?
- Yeah.
We can use the Freon, too.
No, I told you it's gonna be
room temperature.
I know. Just in case.
No, no, wait, wait. Aaron, stop, stop.
I'll just buy the tubing.
This isn't saving us money.
Wait. Did you cut anything?
- Hey, man. How are you?
- Good, Jay.
Should we be wearing goggles?
- Should we be wearing goggles?
- What?
Goggles.
Should we be wearing goggles?
(AARON) Oh, wait, Phillip.
You don't want to come out here.
(ABE) Phillip, grab a mask, OK?
It is, though, right? It's not just me?
(AARON) No, it's definitely smaller, but...
I think it just seems that way.
I mean, take what they have.
OK, minus the coolant, OK?
Which we don't need.
The rest of it is the mercury bath,
which I mean,
you would know better than I do,
but they're probably just showing off.
I mean, if you have it,
you've got to use it, right?
- (ABE) What? Does it hurt?
- No, I didn't feel anything.
That sound is just weirding me out.
Wow.
- What does it feel like?
- I don't know.
I don't know if I'm making it up.
Here.
- Next part. Let's do the next part.
- Yeah. Yeah.
Isn't there some sort of glass
or transparent...
- I don't know.
- Anything we can use as a window? Pyrex?
- Yeah, I'm in.
- OK, drop it.
I don't know of anything
that's not going to leave a gap in the field.
But we got to see what's going on in there.
- How much did that cost?
- Yeah.
- What?
- You want to put my camcorder
inside the box that's so dangerous
we can't look into it.
(AARON) If something happens,
would you pay me back?
(ABE) So we have
a slightly negative pressure in the box.
So we're ready for the argon.
- Wait, which one is that?
- It's the blue one.
- Blue one.
- I weighed it at 77 grams.
I set the scale to decagrams, though.
I'm showing 7.7 decagrams.
Ready for...
0.05 litres of argon.
(HISSING)
Ready?
- Just the plate first, right?
- Right, first just the plate, and then we'll...
(MACHINE HUMMING)
OK, let's just give it a second.
- You want to do the box now?
- Yeah.
- OK, let's go through the checklist, then.
- Aaron, hold on a second.
Let's make sure everything's set up right.
Hold on, Aaron. Wait.
Just wait.
OK.
(MACHINE RUMBLING)
Anything?
- Is this normal?
- I don't know...
- I'm turning it off.
- Wait!
- No, it's frying my camera.
- Not yet!
(MACHINE STOPS RUMBLING)
OK, I didn't do that.
Did we blow something?
Yeah, yeah, we did.
That's destroyed.
- Here, you want to check your camera?
- Yeah.
Let's get this.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
One, two, three.
(BUZZING)
(PHONE BEEPING)
- Hey.
- (AARON) Hey, hey, tell me you're hungry.
Kara's at her mom's and I'm starving.
Uh... Yeah. Yeah, yeah,
I'm hungry. What...
Abe, it's 7:00.
- 'Abe, it's 7:00 at night.
- OK, yeah, I have food...
OK, OK. Wait, wait, wait.
Are those kids there?
Uh, just a sec.
Yeah. Yeah, they're here.
OK, screw that, let's just go somewhere.
I just pulled in, so come on down.
No, wait. Come up here first. I have
some stuff I want to take back to the shop.
All right, but meet me at the door.
OK, all right.
Seriously, meet me at the door.
I'm coming up right now.
I'll do it. OK. All right.
All right, see you.
(SIGNS) OK.
(SIGHS) Hey, Brad.
(CROWD CHEERING ON TV)
What's up, Abe?
- Hey, Brad. How are you?
- Good.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
How long did he say
he was going to be there?
Not long.
I just think if he's got problems,
he's got to fix them. You're not the guy's dad.
I know. I just thought it would be good
to do something charitable.
It definitely is charity.
At least you admit that.
Hey, you feel like a steak?
To eat.
No, I don't want a steak. Let's just grab
some tacos on the way to the shop.
- I have some stuff I want to try out.
- OK.
Uh, we can get some tacos on the way,
and I know where we can get
a steak afterwards.
What are you talking about?
I'm not paying for a steak.
It's stable?
Aaron, it's stable?
- What did you do to this thing?
- Huh? What?
Looks like a dog digested it.
OK, that's the plate.
I rigged this into the box
so I could have some control over the feed.
- I figured it's the easiest way...
- This is controlling the box.
- Right, just the box.
- The plate stays the same.
Yeah, the plate's the same.
What you do is you gradually feed it...
till...
(MACHINE HUMMING)
OK. You hear that? How it's, how it's...
See, I'm not touching it anymore.
It's growing with its own momentum.
It's like a feedback loop,
and it just regulates itself.
And what you do is,
when it gets there...
you bring it back,
and there you go, it coasts.
It's stable.
It stays like that.
So, it works.
- Yeah, it does.
- What is that, like 10%?
It knocks another couple of points off, too,
by the time it reaches the peak.
You may want to come over here
and take a look at this.
- OK, what am I looking at?
- What are we pulling out of the batteries?
I don't know, probably 24 volts.
- I mean, no more than that, right?
- OK.
So, your meter's jacked up.
That's what I figured. So, I tried three others.
I got the exact same thing.
- I spent all last night...
- What was it?
I don't know. I spent all last night
and a two-hour lunch break today
just double-checking everything.
We're missing something.
There's something wrong here.
We're not pulling out
more than we're putting in.
- Slightly more.
- Well, yeah, whatever.
It's not like a volt and a half more
than we're putting in.
I mean, it's probably the batteries.
They're cheap batteries, you know,
probably not regulated right.
It is weird, though.
You want to see something weirder?
OK, let's go over this again.
Two batteries, right? 24 volts?
What are we pulling out of this one?
Just for fun.
Twelve volts.
- How about this one?
- Should be 12 volts.
So, what the hell is this thing?
It doesn't stay like that.
No, I mean, it winds down in a few minutes,
but what does that?
(MACHINE HUM FADING)
(AARON) I don't know.
I'll tell them something.
I'll tell them we're spraying
for bugs or something.
It should just be a day or two anyways.
- Unless you want to bring them in.
- No, no, it's just...
I mean, they have
their work in there, too.
You know, if Phillip finds out about that
or even sees it,
- he's going to have to take it apart.
- I'm just putting a love tweak on it.
Yeah, I know. No, you're right.
Abe, it's my garage, OK?
It's not like they're paying rent.
(MAN) There was value in the thing, clearly.
That they were certain of.
But what is the application?
In a matter of hours, it was everything
from mass transit to satellite launching.
Imagining devices
the size of jumbo jets.
Everything would be cheaper.
It was practical, and they knew it.
But above all that,
beyond the positives,
they knew that the easiest way
to be exploited
is to sell something
they did not yet understand.
So they kept quiet.
The parties would continue.
Any birthday, anniversary, holiday,
maybe some obscure project launch,
it didn't matter. Any reason would do.
What was important is that Thomas Granger,
their last, best hope of funding, show up.
And if he left a little earlier
than they would've liked,
well, he couldn't be blamed.
He was only there
to please his daughter Rachel.
And she was only there to please Abe.
Hey, what did you say
to Mr Granger earlier?
- Did you flip my burger?
- You can't call him Mr Granger.
You have to call him Thomas
or something.
- Go ahead, Robert. Flip it.
- No, because he won't take you seriously.
- He's my dad's age.
- But he thinks we're kids.
If you call him Mr Granger, he looks at you
like you're a six-year-old kid.
He does it with me.
- That's not going to work anymore.
- Why do you have to be so...
(MAN) Abe had taken on the task
of quantifying and explaining the device.
But as weeks became months,
their enthusiasm became a slow realisation
that they were out of their depth.
There he is.
I've been calling you all morning.
- Where'd you call?
- Your work and your cell.
I'm not there.
Really?
- March madness?
- It's Carolina and Michigan.
- Who's up?
- I don't even know. What?
Do you have anything important
at work today?
I hope you're not implying
that any day is unimportant at Cortex Semi.
No, no. Just... Look, I was going to come
give you this big speech
about how we've been friends for a long time
and built up trust, and that whole big thing.
But how about this instead?
If you ditch work this afternoon and promise
to do the few small things that I ask you,
I will in return show you
the most important thing
that any living organism
has ever witnessed.
- (AARON) Well, it looks like mustard to me.
- (ABE) I know, but it's a film.
It's a protein secreted by a fungus
called aspergillus ticor.
He told you that?
No, he knew it was a protein,
but he didn't know where it came from.
All he really did was just take some pictures
with their equipment.
- Hey, guess where we're going.
- Do you know where Will is?
No, why?
The Ariel meeting
is pushed back till Wednesday.
I just thought he was waiting around for it.
Where are you going?
What do they do with engineers
when they turn 40?
- What, Bradshaw?
- Exactly. You know what?
I do know where Will is.
I'll let him know on my way out, OK?
- OK.
- Thanks. Can you meet me out front?
- Are you gonna drive?
- OK, here. Take my keys.
OK, if you can just pretend
that this is the first time I came in.
And if you would
just tell him exactly what you told me...
- OK, so what is it?
- Protein build-up.
(ABE) OK, can you just tell him?
- (ABE) But what kind?
Some fungus. Some fungus.
Where did it come from?
I don't know.
You were supposed to take it to the lab.
Yeah, that's next.
- You were in design, weren't you?
- Yeah.
How did you get over here?
You know what they do
with engineers when they turn 40?
They take them out and shoot them.
What the hell, Abe?
You could've just shown me the pictures.
I want you to believe it.
- Believe what, the protein? I believe you.
- OK, look.
This guy already thinks it's a joke, OK?
So he may be a little defensive.
Really? Why would he think that?
Please.
Aspergillus ticor.
This is a fungus that's everywhere.
It's in our bed, on our skin,
sometimes even our GI tract. Everywhere.
It's basically the reason
you don't leave things
in dark, damp, closed-off places.
Thank you.
Do you have that sample I brought?
(ABE) There it is. Terger. T-E-R-G-E-R.
OK, when I showed you this,
tell him what you thought.
You thought it was a joke, right?
It is a joke.
Right, but how did you know?
Will you show him? Please?
This is how I get protein A
out of aspergillus ticor.
We sweeten it, we agitate it,
we spin it around, we sweeten some more.
- Takes about a month.
- To get the same amount I brought in.
To get the same amount I brought in.
(AARON) So if it's an incubator for fungus,
is that valuable?
- That's not what it is.
- Then what is it?
There's one other way it could secrete
that much protein. It could do it naturally.
But that takes a lot longer.
A lot longer.
But if it has a little moisture
and it's left alone,
it'll start secreting and it'll build up
and build up, but it takes a long time.
- How long?
- A long time.
- More than a few days?
- Yes.
Then how long?
He says to get the same amount of protein
that we had,
the same amount
that I was wiping off every five days
and five days later it would accumulate,
he says it would take about
five to six years.
- I want to belittle this guy.
- Exactly.
So I said screw it,
and I put my watch in there.
- And?
- I want you to do it.
- Where is it? The box?
- I took it back to the shop.
- Wait, digital or old mechanical?
- Exactly. I did both.
- And what?
- I want you to do it.
(ABE) We thought that we were
degrading gravity, right?
That we were blocking that information.
But I think we're doing more than that.
I think we're blocking more than that.
Did you notice
when you were controlling the feed,
did you notice it was parabolic?
OK, it's important.
Parabolas are important. Here, look at this.
I don't know, Abe.
Now I'm going to start it up and let it run
for 60 seconds with nothing in it, OK?
- It's empty this time.
- That's 22...
In all the equations that describe motion
and heat and entropy.
Just one minute. Just a second.
In all Feynman diagrams, what's the one
variable that you can turn negative
and still get rational answers for?
- One minute out here...
- It's not mass, it's not...
- 22 hours, 27 minutes in the box.
- It's odd, it's an odd number.
How many minutes is that?
That's 1,347 minutes.
OK, yeah, 1,347, man,
you got that fast.
Why is it odd?
How'd you know it was odd?
Because this is it, OK?
This is what's going on.
There's an "A" end and there's a "B" end.
Let's say the "A" end is 12:00
and the "B" end is 12:01.
All right? We start the machine
with the weeble at the "A" end.
- It travels forward...
- You got to write this down.
- Aaron, there's nothing to write down.
- I'm writing it down.
Fine, it travels forward
normally towards the "B" end,
and when it gets there,
the feed runs down parabolically
until it should stop, but it doesn't.
It curves back around towards the "A" end.
When it gets back to the "A" end...
Now, curve that around.
OK, now the weeble has experienced
a total of two minutes, and again it curves...
(AARON) Back around. It curves parabolically.
Right. So, it comes back around again,
and it does this about 1,300 times,
and when it finally exits on the "B" end,
it's travelled an odd number
of forward and backward trips.
Now, what is so special about 1,300?
Why is it about 1,300? Why isn't it exact?
- This is not empirical.
- Here, give me that.
I don't know why it's not exact.
There's some sort of probability there.
OK, every time it hits the "B" end
there's a chance, OK?
A small chance it won't
curve back around towards the "A" end.
And for some reason, it takes about
1,300 trips before it finally does.
But it does have to exit, or else we wouldn't
be able to see it afterwards.
OK, let's take a look at this.
Yeah, 22 hours, 14 minutes.
1,334 minutes.
Even.
Enter at the "B" end.
Exit at the "B" end.
(ABE) I just want you to see it
the way I saw it.
I am trying, OK? I really am, here.
Look, everything we're putting in that box
becomes ungrounded.
And I don't mean grounded like to the earth.
I mean, not tethered.
We're blocking whatever keeps them
moving forward, so they flip-flop.
Inside the box, it's like a street,
and both ends are cul-de-sacs.
I mean, this isn't frame dragging
or Wormhole matching.
- This is Basic Mechanics and Heat 101.
- This is not mechanics and heat.
We can publish.
- Yeah, we can publish.
- No, I mean we can really publish.
Aaron, the weeble's stupid.
It can't move.
I mean, even if we were
to put the weeble in at point "B"
it's still just going
to bounce around back and forth,
until it gets kicked out at the "B" end.
But if it were smart...
it could enter at the "B" end
and exit at the "A" end before it flips back.
You're talking about making a bigger one.
You're talking about
making a bigger one.
I... I didn't say anything.
You're the one talking about it.
So, you believe me?
No, I don't.
- Come on. Let's go get a drink or something.
- Yeah.
- (AARON) We're going to have to move it.
- We will.
We need a box big enough
for a person to fit into, right?
As far as turning it on...
(ABE) I was testing the box. It turns out
that over half the rings are redundant.
The inner ring is strong enough on its own,
so it actually makes the plate smaller.
- No.
- And there's a lot more that's unnecessary.
Look, what we can do
is take a lot of these small plates
and surround a container
with a web of them.
How small?
Well, I mean,
it should be accumulative,
So a lot of mini-fields
equal one big one, right?
Yeah, I mean, yeah.
Sum of series, that makes sense.
What I was going to say though, is we need
to find some place where we can put it,
and turn it on and it won't be disturbed.
- I mean some place...
- We could just lock it in a closet.
No, safer than a closet.
Some place where someone's not going to go
poking around and messing with it.
And climate-controlled.
Yeah, yeah, so whatever,
we'll find some place.
But I mean, so, if we go your route,
with what, a bunch of mini-fields?
That's a lot of work. We'd have to...
I mean, how many days is that?
Abe, you know what we could use?
You know what we could use?
What?
I know we've seen
a lot of crazy things lately, OK?
And I know you're still trying to put it
all together in a way that makes sense.
- But you got everything.
- No, no, I don't.
Look, I just want you to understand
that what's next is not a prank, OK?
I wouldn't do that to you,
and I'm not doing that to you.
- So when you see this, you can't yell...
- Did you bring one with you?
...or make any noise or run anywhere. OK?
I know you probably feel
like you're being tricked or made fun of.
But you're not, OK?
I promise you. You're not.
OK?
Who was that, Abe?
Let's just wait.
Six minutes.
Look, you sure you're OK to drive?
What did you do all day?
The first time through?
I spent the day
in a hotel room in Russelfield.
- Look, I'll just meet you back at the shop.
- Wonder what I did.
- Guess I went back to work.
- Yeah, probably.
Probably just worked, I guess.
Yeah, probably so.
Look, now that I know about this, Abe...
(PHONE RINGING)
Don't do this again, OK?
Not where it affects me.
Go ahead.
Hi, Rachel.
(AARON MUMBLING)
(WATER RUNNING)
Why not the lottery?
Well, we can if you want,
but it's not till Saturday.
But even if we win the full $10 million,
it's only a couple of hundred thousand a year
for, what, the next 30 years?
Only.
- And that's just one good trade.
- A couple of days like this.
That was just running a test.
In and out.
OK. Well, I want to do what you did.
OK? Exactly what you did.
(ABE) OK, the first thing I did
is call in sick.
- (AARON) OK, I did that.
- And then I drove to the storage facility.
OK, but I need to drop
Lauren off at school first.
OK, then meet me there.
We're going to need both cars.
But we need to park yours way down
the road, out of sight of the facility.
- Wait, why are we doing that?
- Because we need a ride home.
- What is that...
- No, it'll make sense.
OK, I'll be patient.
When I got to the storage room,
I flooded the box with argon,
and then I had to tighten it up
to secure the leaks.
- There's leaks?
- There's always leaks.
At 8:30am I set the timer for 15 minutes,
I jumped in the car,
and drove to Russelfield.
- OK, I lost it.
- What?
Why the timer?
Because the moment
we start those machines
is the moment we'll end up
getting out of them, and...
Right. Got it. Sorry.
I don't want to be standing around
when they do.
Yep.
(ABE) While I was on the road at 8:45,
the machine kicked on by itself, and...
by 8:49 it was completely warmed up.
In Russelfield I got a hotel room
and tried to isolate myself.
Wait, what do you mean, "isolate"?
I mean, I closed the windows,
I unplugged everything in the room,
the telephone,
TV, clock, radio, everything.
I didn't want to take the chance
of running into someone I knew,
or seeing something
on the news that might...
If we're dealing with causality,
and I don't even know for sure...
- I just..
- What?
Took myself out of the equation.
- (AARON) Err on the side of caution.
- Yes.
Well, then what did you do all clay?
I just sat there.
I mean, I had some books, but...
(AARON) What? Were you nervous?
Yeah. It's just mind-numbing,
all the second-guessing.
Evacipate.
At 2:30pm,
I stopped by Williams Medical Supply,
and picked up a class "E"
oxygen tank and mask.
I called my mutual fund company
and asked which stock in their mid-cap fund
had the greatest percentage gain that day.
The idea was just to get enough information
for one good trade.
(AARON) When we go, can we just download
chart data? Trade on each movement?
Yeah, but if we do that,
I want to use the library in Russelfield,
use their computers.
So, I got to the storage room at about 3:15,
and out off the power to the box.
It cycled down
to a tolerable level at about 3:19.
You see, the trick is to get in
after it reaches a comfortable level,
but before it shuts off completely.
There's a window there.
So, does it hurt?
Yeah. Yeah, it does a little.
It's not bad, though,
if you wait for the right time.
It's like a small static shock.
Once you're in, you're fine, though.
What?
(AARON) I know you've done it, OK?
And I can only assume that you don't have
cancer or male impotence because of it.
But I mean, what is your opinion
on how safe this thing is?
Aaron, I can imagine no way
in which this thing would be considered
anywhere remotely close to safe.
All I know is I spent six hours in there,
and I'm still alive.
You still want to do it?
(METAL THUDDING)
(MACHINE HUMMING)
I set the alarm on my stopwatch
for six hours.
I regulated the O2 tank,
took some Dramamine and tried to sleep.
Did you?
- What?
- Did you sleep?
Not at first.
You know, I've never considered
myself claustrophobic,
but I started sweating and I couldn't find
the right flow rate on the tank,
and I was breathing a lot differently
than I was when I was testing it
on the outside.
Eventually, I settled down, and...
I don't know,
maybe it was the Dramamine kicking in,
but I remember this moment in there,
in the dark,
with the reverberation of the machine.
It was maybe the most content
I've ever been.
I woke up on my own without the alarm
and waited for the machine to cool down.
Cool down from my perspective.
It got to a point
where it sounded safe to get out
but the stopwatch still showed
a couple minutes
so I trusted the math and waited.
(METAL THUDDING)
(AARON SHIVERING)
That is not a static shock, Abe.
OK, please stop it.
(ABE) You got out too soon.
You have to wait for the stopwatch
so that you know the gain is low enough.
So, we're back here?
Yeah, we're here.
It's 8:50, Tuesday morning.
All right. Give me a few minutes.
(ABE) From there it was easy.
The bulk of the work was done.
I just left everything the way I found it.
I left the machine alone
and didn't turn it off or anything,
and just cleared out of there.
(AARON) OK, so that way,
your double would find everything
exactly the same later that day
and get in the box?
Right, right, but also, at that point,
I or my double or someone
was in the box coming backwards.
So who knows what that would've done
if I would have turned the machine off.
(AARON) Definitely. Definitely.
So, they're one-time use only.
So then, at that moment, since my double
was on the way to the hotel room in my car,
I had to take a taxi home. But when we go,
we'll be able to use your truck.
- You have a margin account, right?
- Yeah. I do now. What are we buying?
Good. Today, before 12:30, we're going
to buy as many shares as we can of RGWU.
Then they'll announce
that their earnings for the quarter
are three-and-a-half times consensus,
and the stock will nearly double
in afternoon trading.
- What do they do?
- What do you mean?
What does... What does this company do?
Do they make things or...
I don't know. It doesn't matter.
All that matters is that the price goes up.
And the volume is so high
that the number of shares we're trading
is not going to affect the price.
You really don't know what they do?
(COMPUTER KEYS CLACKING)
That's why you were talking
about a mid-cap fund,
so the volume
would be high enough to hide us.
- Do you think that's too cautious?
- I don't know.
I know there's
a lot of other stocks out there
that do a lot more than double,
but this is my first day.
(ABE) My God.
- (AARON) She's not getting paid, already.
- (KARA) I know, Abe.
- (AARON) This is what she does.
- That's the question.
(ABE) I know, so what's the answer?
I mean, you've got the $400 billion,
you've gone the charity route,
you have this perfect 100-room mansion
with matching his and her yachts
and helicopter pads.
I mean, basically, you have absolute impunity
to do whatever you want.
- Nobody can touch you.
- Yeah.
- You're fresh back from this two-year...
- Above the law.
Well, absolutely, well above.
You're fresh back
from this two-year world-galloping vacation.
- How do you fill your day? What do you do?
- Abe, I know that's the question,
but it's not a real question,
so why does it matter?
(ABE) So what's the answer?
Babe, he knows that's the question, OK?
He's asking you the question.
Well, what do you mean?
What would I do with my life
- or what would I do tomorrow?
- My God, either.
Well...
I'd have to do something constructive.
I'd have to do something that would help.
- Something to make you feel good.
- I know. That's fantastic. Good.
My wife. So good.
So pure. You are pure.
- (KARA) Shut up. Why did you ask, then?
- This is what I would do.
I would wake up tomorrow morning
and I'd go over to Gabriel Capital Inc.
And I would tell Joseph Platts' receptionist
that I'm there to see him.
And when he comes out,
I would ram my fist
through the flat of his nose.
Just one good punch, one good pow.
- That's amazing. It's about time.
- That's so great.
Where did this come from? You're the one
that's always defending the guy.
- It's only natural.
- I'd only do it though if I knew that
you know, no one would find out
or get hurt or anything.
Like, I wish that there was a way
that I could do it,
and, uh, go back and tell myself not to.
Cos I just want to know what it feels like.
That's all, really.
I'm so proud.
Finally, my husband, the hero.
You can't do that.
- I know.
- Did you call pest control?
Babe, they're birds.
You don't want a bunch
of dead baby birds up there, do you?
They don't sound like birds.
She thinks there are rats in the attic.
(MAN) But the idea had been spoken,
and the words wouldn't go back
after they'd been uttered aloud.
So you're understanding this, right?
Look, Abe, you don't have to sell me
on not doing this, OK?
I don't really think I told you...
The thing is, even if you do stop yourself,
your double, from hitting Platts,
then why would he, your double,
get back in the box?
(MAN) And with no need for it,
no possible real-world application,
no advantage at all to be gained from it,
the idea stayed.
How would you do it?
I wouldn't.
- Just for fun.
- I still wouldn't.
- But what if there was a way to...
- Look, Abe, look.
I'm not going to pretend like I know
anything about paradoxes, you know?
Or what follows them. And honestly,
I really don't believe in any of that crap.
I mean, kill your mom
before you were born, whatever.
It has to work itself out somehow.
- I don't know, man.
- Look, this is what I know for sure, OK?
About the worst thing in the world
is to know that the moment you're
experiencing has already been defined,
that this is the second or third time through,
or whatever, and...
do you ever feel, you know, like...
I don't know, maybe things aren't right,
like maybe your life is in disarray
or just not what you would like
and you start to wonder, you know,
"What caused this?
How did things get like this?"
You know, people are always
blaming their parents, you know,
as if their mom would have breastfed them,
their lives would have turned out different.
- Bunch of whiners.
- Yeah, they're a bunch of whiners.
But what if it wasn't
something you wondered about.
What if you knew for sure this is not the way
things are supposed to be.
I'm not like that.
I'm not into the whole
"destiny, there's-only-one-right-way" thing.
Abe, I'm not, either, OK?
But what's worse?
You know, thinking you're being paranoid
or knowing you should be?
You don't have to look at me like that.
I'm OK.
(ABE) No, I just assumed that you would.
I mean, I trust her.
I know that when I decided to tell you...
- Not that I was ever thinking of not...
- Decided to tell me? Thank you.
I just knew that you're married
and that there's no secrets,
and anything I tell you, she'll know.
- It's not a matter of trust.
- No, I know.
It's just how much better will it be
if in a few days, you know,
I surprise her and we all just fly to Costa Rica
or somewhere for a month?
You know,
we'll let her understand it gradually.
- Maybe do some real estate shopping...
- For now, though, if you wanted to,
you can just tell her
you had a good day in the market.
You don't understand. No.
You don't understand the questions
that come with that, OK?
But we'll explain it to her,
and we'll all just take some time
to figure out what's next,
which, right away I think,
should be building a bigger box,
like the size of a room or something,
at least more than one person
could fit into it.
Safe or not,
the thing feels like a coffin the way it is.
By the way, this is our guy.
What's the volume?
Five-and-a-half.
What's the return? Holy...
Yeah. No, I can't beat that.
But mainly, I guess I was just talking
about Robert and Phillip, you know.
I don't want to tell them.
I know they have a lot invested
in the group, and I just...
I don't want to tell them.
Abe, if you need me
to take the guilt on this one, fine.
OK? I accept it gladly. It's mine.
At the end of this week,
they can have whatever they want, OK?
I'll turn over patent rights
on everything from the last two years.
They can have the equipment,
the garage, the house.
They can have my truck
if that makes you feel better, OK?
But I am not telling them a thing about this.
We're not.
(AARON) God,
everything is so different in there.
You can feel how cut off you are,
you know.
It's this entirely separate world
and you encompass most of it.
(ABE) And the sound.
Isn't the sound different on the inside?
It's like it's singing.
I guess you can't hear it on the outside...
I had this dream in there.
- About what?
- (SIGHS)
I was on or near the ocean,
and I just kept hearing the surf.
It was so uneventful.
At night.
And the tide kept coming in and out.
- Yeah.
Hey, whoa, come here for a second, man.
What's on your hand?
- Are you bleeding?
- That is blood.
- Turn around.
- You see it?
- Where is it coming from?
- It's your notebook.
- Aaron, it's you.
- What is this?
My gosh, it's on your ear.
Your ear's bleeding. Man.
Give me that. I got it.
- Is that normal? This isn't normal.
- For the machine?
No, for people.
You think it's the machine?
I got it.
Great. We can actually
get some work done today.
Hi, guys. What's going on?
I always seem to get a lot more done
when I'm not locked out.
(ABE) Yeah.
He said they had to spray again.
Yeah. But he can't tell us about it
in advance. ls hero even here?
Besides, you never see anything
around here but those geckos, anyway.
- Oh, I know.
- Yeah, I think it's for the geckos.
- (BOTH) What?
- (PHILLIP) Why?
(ROBERT) Oh, hey, man,
thanks for the present.
Yeah... yeah,
how is that working out for you?
You know what?
You guys, both of you,
- you make fun, but there is a difference.
- Wait. What did you call him?
- What?
- When you walked in? What did you say?
- He really didn't tell you about it?
- No.
All right. Rachel's ex-boyfriend
walks into my birthday party with a shotgun.
- What?
- Swear to God.
(AARON) Yeah, Abe.
I've already gotten that speech from Kara.
You're going to get it from me.
You have a wife and kid.
It's funny how you two are the only people
who have a problem with it.
- Everybody else thinks I did a good thing.
- Well, you didn't.
You can't go risking your life and especially
the welfare of Kara and Lauren
for someone like Rachel.
She practically begged
for this to happen to her.
I figured at least you'd understand this.
Understand what?
You've never been like this.
That's what I mean. You see...
You see how different things are now.
Different?
How are things different?
You see it, OK? I know you do.
Look, that was the night you had told me
everything about the machine, OK?
And everything you told me
was so fresh in my head,
and when I saw this guy,
you know, I'm looking at him.
I wasn't going to let him do that.
I wasn't going to let him
scare people like that. And I...
I know it was stupid, OK?
But, I mean, this whole idea,
this whole thing that we're doing...
it just took some getting used to for me.
I wasn't completely acclimated to it.
OK. If it was just you
you had to worry about,
you know, I'd still think you're stupid.
But now, you have a family now.
And God, especially now,
to risk anything would be completely crazy.
I know, OK?
And the thing is,
I know you know that, but you've got to...
I know, OK? I know.
Filby!
You little sack of... You know what?
Even if you see him, don't tell me.
It's not my fault if I don't know.
I just hope the thing runs away.
Then what are we doing out here?
She worries about the cat,
so you look for the cat. It's what you do.
- I don't know.
- What do you mean?
It's just a little embarrassing.
The storage room guy sees us
come in together but he never sees us leave.
Yeah, but what do you think
the receptionist thinks
about two guys that come and get a room
for six hours every day?
(PHONE RINGING)
Did you unplug this?
(PHONE KEEPS RINGING)
You brought your cell phone?
Can I check the caller ID?
Yeah, we're not... We're not back.
Yeah. Yeah,
but you can't take it back with you, OK?
This is Aaron. Hey, babe.
Yeah, I'm not there. I had to come downtown
and hold some of these guys' hands.
Tell me.
(SIGHS) That sounds good.
No, I've got to eat with these off site fags.
Save mine, though.
I'll have it later.
OK.
Yeah. Um... yeah, 6:00.
(CHEERING ON TV)
(MAN TALKING ON TV)
What?
- What?
- We're supposed to win this by two.
They just turned over
with the 12 on the clock.
We have to foul.
- No.
- No, we have to foul.
What? No, we foul here,
they miss the first free throw,
they come back with a three, that's right.
That's right.
Yeah.
Man, are you hungry?
I haven't eaten since later this afternoon.
What's up, you guys?
(PHONE RINGING)
- You have to be kidding me.
- I'm sorry.
I'm sorry,
I forgot it was in my pocket.
- It's Kara.
- Yeah.
How do cell phones work?
If there's two duplicate phones
and I call the same number,
do they both ring at the same time,
or is there...
- That's not how they work.
- They both ring. It's a radio signal.
No, it's a network.
The network checks each area.
When it finds the phone, it stops ringing.
It only... It rings the first one.
This one's ringing.
Right.
So the one your double has
in Russelfield can't be.
Right. I think we broke symmetry.
- Are you sure that's how cell phones work?
- No.
You feel all right?
- I feel fine. Do you?
- Yeah.
(CAR ALARM BLARING)
(CAR HORN HONKING)
- (ABE) Is Kara asleep? Did I wake you up?
- Yeah.
No, not me,
it felt more like a nap.
I think my body's getting used
to these 36-hour days.
What's going on?
We can do this, but we have to do it now.
Do you have his home address?
Why now?
We were planning on taking a trip tomorrow,
right? Just like today?
- Yeah, for stocks.
- OK, well...
Half an hour ago I was asleep.
This car alarm woke me up.
These kids were down skating by,
hitting every car on the block.
So we go right now, do our business
at the Platts', get back in the box,
and come back to right before
those kids are setting off the alarms.
All we'd really have to do is stand there
in plain sight to scare them off.
So that way my double
sleeps through the night,
they don't have
the conversation we're having now,
and they get in the box tomorrow as usual.
- Yeah. They'll be changed. But...
- Yeah, but at least they'll get in the box.
Wait, how do we go back that far
if the machines haven't been running?
Have they been running?
Yeah. I started going by at five o'clock
and turning them on, 5:00pm.
I just got tired of the whole
unanswerable question...
Are we doing this as an experiment,
or are we doing this for me?
- A little of both.
- Five o'clock.
If we get this done by 3:00,
that's ten hours in the box.
I've got the O2 tanks in the car.
It's going to be a long day.
- Is that...
- Is that Rachel's car?
No, that's not Rachel's, that's her dad's.
They have the same kind.
Did you see that?
That's Mr... That's Mr Granger.
That's Thomas. He's sitting in that car.
What?
I swear that was him.
What the hell is he doing...
just sitting outside my house
at 2:00 in the morning?
I don't believe this.
What, is he following us?
Abe, what are you doing?
- What are you doing?
- Let's just see what he wants.
No, let's just get out
of my neighbourhood first.
- But why?
- Come on.
- Did you see him today?
- No.
I did. I saw him this afternoon.
Around 6:00.
You sure you didn't see him
when we drove past?
No, what?
I'm almost positive this afternoon
he was clean-shaven. In fact, I know he was.
He was ready to go to some function
with his wife.
He looks like he's got, like,
a two or three-day growth now.
- Are you sure?
- No, I'm not sure, but I think so.
Hey, Rachel. Hey, this is Abe.
Did I wake you up?
Yeah, hey, can I get your dad's number
from you real quick?
Yeah. OK, go ahead.
- All right, yeah, thanks.
- Wait, what's he doing?
He's just sitting there.
He got out for a second and I don't know,
I thought he was coming over,
and then he got back in the car.
I think he's drunk.
Hi. Sorry to call so late.
May I speak to Thomas Granger,
please?
Yeah, this is James Miller
from Putney and Myers.
Hi, Mr Granger?
Thomas Granger?
Hey! Hey! What are you doing here?
Come here!
(DOG BARKING)
What happened?
I'm OK. I slipped.
(DOOR OPENING)
I just want to know what box he used.
You built one for you, right? Just the one?
Yeah. How many do you think I made?
And these are set right.
I turned them on at 5:00.
He could have used one
and gone back to 5:00.
He could be in one of them right now.
I say we shut them off
and see if he's in there.
Were you planning on talking to him?
Just tell me if you were.
I'm not going to be mad, just tell me.
No, I promise you. You know I wouldn't.
Are you sure you wouldn't?
You're the one that can't get near
without passing out.
There is no way
I would tell anyone about this. No way.
- Can you think of any reason you might?
- No, I can't.
Sometimes we do things,
but don't know how we got to that point.
- No, I can't.
- Can't what?
I can't think of any reason why I would.
I can't either.
What if it was an emergency?
- So you'd do it if it was an emergency?
- No, I don't know. What, so you might, then?
I don't know.
What kind of emergency?
(MAN) The permutations were endless.
- (PHONE RINGS)
- OK, go ahead.
They tried again going to the source,
but even while keeping him separated
from Abe by two rooms...
Ask him his name.
...Thomas Granger's condition
could only be described as vegetative.
What did he say?
From this they deduced
that the problem was recursive,
but beyond that, found themselves admitting,
against their own nature,
and once again,
that the answer was unknowable.
What do you think he changed?
It couldn't have been much.
We didn't have any contact with him
in the three hours
he could've done anything.
I know he changed this.
I know we weren't having
this conversation the first time through.
- So you don't know what we lost.
- Really, it could not have been much.
It doesn't matter how much.
It just matters that it's changed.
- Look, Abe, I know what you're saying, OK?
- (MAN) The question should have been
what to do with the comatose man
in the guest bedroom.
We can wait this out.
But in Abe's mind,
he was already compiling the list.
Two milligrams of oral triazolam
every seven hours
induces a safe sleep state
and a minimal metabolic rate.
At this continued state of rest,
the human body breathes
0.3 litres of oxygen a minute,
or roughly 2,000 litres in four days.
A class E oxygen tank holds 625 litres.
To maintain hydration,
the body cycles through a minimum
of two-and-a-half litres of water per day.
Any food would be a luxury,
but the small tank
of medical-grade nitrous oxide
would be needed on the other side.
Past the room that contained their machines,
and up two levels,
he made his way to another room
where he had stored
what I will refer to from here on
as the failsafe machine.
(GAS HISSING)
There he is.
I've been calling you all morning.
Really?
Your cell and work.
- I'm not there.
- Really?
I don't even know. What?
I'm just tired.
I hope you're not implying
that any day is unimportant at Cortex Semi.
(ABE) I was going to come
give you this big speech
about how we've been friends for a long time
and built up trust, and that whole thing.
But how about this instead?
If you ditch work this afternoon and promise
to do the few small things that I ask you,
I will in return show you
the most important thing
that any living organism
has ever witnessed.
(MAN) At this point there would
have been some discussion.
Abe would, of course,
want to know how.
Aaron would have to explain
all about the storage manifest
and how it showed two rooms
under the name Abram Terger.
Then Abe would need to know how.
Aaron would explain
that when he went up there
and found the failsafe running,
he knew exactly what it was.
But Abe would ask, "How?"
And then the bit
about the modular design of the coffins,
and how it meant he could fold one up
and take it back inside another.
They are not one-time use only.
They are recyclable, Aaron would say.
"How?" Abe would ask.
And Aaron would describe
how simple things become
when you know precisely
what someone will have for breakfast
even in a world of tamper-proof lids.
How?
And that's where
I would have entered the story.
Or exited, depending on your reference.
Because when Aaron came back
the second time, it wasn't so easy.
He wasn't expecting me
to put up a fight,
and by that time
he was too exhausted to take me.
But for reasons
that are only evident to me now,
I understood that he simply wanted it more.
That he just had more invested.
So I left.
He had already performed the task,
as I had intended to,
of recording the conversations of the day,
just in case.
Through that earpiece
he had a three-second lead on the world.
Aaron, you need some sleep.
Some real sleep.
I can't. I've got a schedule.
He had but to speak aloud the words
that came into his head,
and those around him would fall in line.
(AARON ON EARPIECE) This is track 3.
Abe is bringing my car around
and I'm on my way to the court.
I'll see Will there.
I'll invite him to the party and make sure
he's bringing Rachel's boyfriend.
- 'Hey, Will.'
- 'Hey.
- (AARON) Will, hey.
- (WILL) You pretentious prick!
You pretentious prick.
What the hell is that? Your cell phone?
- No, it's a radio.
- 'You look like secret service.
- You look like secret service.
- Ariel meeting is moved to Wednesday.
What? What the hell
am I hanging around here for?
- Yeah, I know. I'm sorry.
- (WILL) Nice shot, Aaron.
Prick. That is ugly, Aaron.
(WILL) We could have used
that last week against TI.
(WILL) At least you've got
your golf game, right?
I see you've been practising.
You come out here with your $3-tie
and think you can play white ball.
- Don't worry, I'm not going to tell anyone.
- (AARON) What are you doing tonight?
Hey. What are you doing tonight?
I was supposed to be in Raleigh,
but thanks to you guys I missed my flight.
- You know Robert?
- Yeah.
He's got a birthday tonight.
Why don't you come out?
- I'm just going to hang out with my cousin.
- Bring him. Rachel will be there.
- Oh, big reunion.
- Exactly.
That should be fun.
I don't think I'm doing this.
Why not?
Because I can think of about a million
different ways that this can happen
and nobody comes anywhere near
getting hurt.
I can call her and see
if she wants to do something else
or better yet, not even talk to her at all,
and she won't even know about the party.
That's good for tonight.
What about tomorrow?
- And every other day?
- I'll take care of tomorrow, tomorrow.
Yeah, you'll watch her all the time.
This guy is crazy enough
to walk into a roomful of people
waving a shotgun around.
What do you think he's going to do
if he ever finds her alone?
This way we know exactly what happens.
We have complete control over it.
At the end of the night,
this guy is arrested and goes to jail.
That's the way it goes.
Your words, not mine.
Now come on. It has to be you.
She said she was there because
you told her you would be there.
Don't tell me I came back
and did this for nothing.
He doesn't fire?
- No. He didn't fire.
- Not even when you rushed him?
No, he didn't the time I wasn't there.
He didn't the time I was,
when I rushed him.
And from what Robert tells you,
he didn't do it tonight.
He doesn't have the nerve. I mean the guy...
We know everything.
OK? We're prescient.
We can still be careful.
Maybe we can get to the gun
without him knowing.
We definitely can.
He leaves it in the truck before he goes in.
I mean, we don't even need to,
but if it makes you feel better...
What's wrong with our hands?
What do you mean?
Why can't we write like normal people?
I don't know.
I can see the letters.
I know what they should look like.
I just can't get my hand to make them easily.
Try comparing it to your left hand.
That looks the same.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hey, Rachel.
Yeah, yeah.
Hey, guess what today is?
No, no.
It's your friend Robert's birthday.
He says he likes records,
so I got him "The Best of Bread".
No, no, real records, like vinyl.
(MAN) I can tell you with certainty
what I did that night when it was my turn.
But I think it would do little good,
because what the world remembers
the actuality, the last revision,
is what counts, apparently.
So how many times did it take Aaron
as he cycled through
the same conversations
lip-synching trivia over and over?
How many times would it take
before he got it right?
Three? Four?
Twenty?
I've decided to believe that only one more
would have done it.
I can almost sleep at night
if there's only one more.
Slowly and methodically
he reverse-engineered a perfect moment.
He took from his surroundings what
was needed and made of it something more.
And once the details
had been successfully navigated,
there would be nothing left to do
but wait for the conflict.
Maybe the obligatory
last-minute moral debate
until the noise of the room
escalates into panic
and background screams
as the gunman walks in.
And eventually he must have got it perfect,
and it must have been beautiful
with all the praise and adoration
he had coming.
He had probably saved lives, after all.
Who knows what would have happened
if he hadn't been there?
(AARON) Look...
I know that things are bad, OK?
I know that you don't agree
with what I've done.
I know that you're upset,
and to be honest I'm not too happy
with you, either, right now.
But you know that this is going to pass.
So let's just go.
Let's get out there. Let's go somewhere
where we don't speak the language.
Aaron, we don't have
the money back here
and we'd have to steal
our own passports.
Money? We'll make money.
They have sports betting in Vegas.
March madness?
We'll make enough in one night
to finance a thousand vacations.
- Passports.
- You know they're not using theirs anyways.
(BANGING)
Now, come on. I'm thinking Star City.
Check out the cosmonaut training grounds.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
I'm staying here.
Why?
(BANGING CONTINUES)
(AARON) They'll be building
their own boxes in another day.
And yours already knows
what they've built.
You're not going to be able
to watch them forever.
(ABE) The box Abe is building
won't work.
He's got it wired wrong.
And if they fix that,
I'll start actually taking pieces out of it.
It's just a gimmick.
It doesn't work anymore.
And your double will say
they have to move on to something else.
- And mine will agree. They're friends.
- You're staying? Why?
Why? Let's see,
why would Abe stay?
What possible reason
could there be to be here?
I guess that it just won't
go back far enough, will it?
Tell you what,
why don't you take Kara and Lauren
and put them in the box,
and then you and Aaron can each keep a set
and you'll both have families
and you can stop feeding off it.
- They'll come back.
- You can each keep a set in a hemisphere.
And I don't think there's ever been
any reason to show you what I'm capable of
but I'm telling you this now.
Go out there
and do whatever the hell you want.
There's no way in the world
I can stop you.
But don't come back here,
and don't come near them.
Any of them.
(MAN) Now I have repaid any debt
I may have owed you.
You know all that I know.
My voice is the only proof
that you will have of the truth of any of this.
I might have written a letter
with my signature,
but my handwriting
is not what it used to be.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Maybe you've had the presence of mind
to record this.
That's your prerogative.
You will not be contacted by me again.
Good morning.
Every half metre.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Everywhere.
And if you look, you will not find me.